جنیفر
Jennifer, why bring so many of
چرا انقدر از وینسنت عکس آوردی؟
Vincent's pictures?
تو هر روز تو مدرسه با اونی.
You'll be with him everyday over there in school
مامان، دستکش وینسنت هم توی چمدون بزار
Mammy, put Vincent's mitt in my luggage, too
ممنون
Thank you
فتی میخوای اینم بیارمش
Fatty, should I bring him this one
یا اینو؟
or this one?
هیچکدوم ،
Neither, he won't even
اون حتی به فرودگاه نمیاد
pick you up at the airport
اون توی بوستون باید بازی کنه
He has to play match in Boston
همیشه به وینسنت فکر میکنم
Always thinking of Vincent
حالا تصویر خواهر زادتو فراموش نکن.
Now don't forget your cousin's picture
مدتی برام طول کشید که ترغیبش کنم تا بیاد دنبالت
It took me a while to persuade him
to pick you up
اون حتی برات یه آپارتمان هم پیاده کرده
He even found you an apartment
چه عوضی
What a jerk
عوضی؟
Jerk?
اون مدیر ارتباطاتی یه شرکت داخل شهره
He's a community leader in Chinatown
خونه و ماشین داره مث یه شاه زندگی میکنه
Owns a house and a car, lives like a king
اون قبلا ملوان بوده
He used to be a sailor
و مردم دست نشانده صداش میکنن
and people call him... Figurehead
دست نشانده؟ چه اسم عجیبی
Figurehead? What a weird name
اون تقریبا باید کسی برای خودش باشه
He must be quite somebody to...
که اینجوری صداش میزنن
be called that
بفرما، این اردک سوخاری رو ببر
Here, take this barbecued duck with you
هیچکس اردک سوخاری با خودش توی هواپیما نمیبره
Nobody carries a duck onto the plane.
دیوونگیه
It is crazy
بگیرش، بیست ساعت پروازه
Take it, its a 20-hour flight
خانوم ها و آقایان
کاپیتان شما،نلسون صحبت میکنه
Ladies and gentlemen.
This is your Captain Nelson speaking.
بزودی در نیویورک فرود میایم
We'll soon be landing
in New York's Kennedy Airport.
از شما بابت همراهیتون تشکر میکنم
We'd like to thank you for flying with us
و امیدوارم از اقامتتون در نیویورک لذت ببرید
And hope your staying in New York
will be a pleasant one
دما در نیویورک 75 درجه فارنهایت است
The temperature in New York City
is 75 Fahrenheit
و ساعت 4:30 بعد از ظهر است
The local time is 4:30 p.m.
از همراهی‌شما متشکرم
Thank you for flying with us
از اقامت تون لذت ببرید
To enjoy your staying
جنفر
Jen Fer...
جنیفر کیه
Who's this Jenfer?
چه اهمیتی داره ؟ برو دنبالش
Who cares? Just pick her up
JenfeM Jen Fer...
پارک اینجا مجاز نیست
Parking is not allowed here!
اوهایو..کونیچیوا
Ohayo. .connichiwa...
بیا تو سریع
Get in, quick
نه، تو باید همین الان بری.
No, you have to leave immediately
اوهایو کونیچیوا
O[iayo. .connichiwa...
جن فر
Jen Fer...
I'm Jennifer
You are Jen Fer?
آره. تو هم مترسکی؟
Right. You're Figurehead?
تو سیزدهمین خواهرزاده چهارمین عمه منی؟
You are my 4th aunts 13 niece?
باشه برو چمدون رو بردار و بیار
Okay. Go get the luggage, move it
کنار وایسید کنار وایسید
Step aside. Step aside
Hot wateM Hot wateM
Sayonara...! Sayonara...!
Sayonara...
Go...you must go. Get out of here
همه چیزو داخل ماشین بزار.
Put everything into the car
ممنون، اینا دوستاتن؟
Thank you...they're your friends?
آره، اونی که زشته یه بزدل خالصه
Yup. The ugly one is Cow, a real coward...
که تظاهر میکنه خیلی آدم شجاعیه
pretending to be tough
اون زشت تره خیلی احمق
The even uglier one is Bull
همیشه بقیه مسخره‌اش میکنن
He is always bullied by others
خب پس اسم تو باید جالب تر از همه باشه
So your name is the most interesting
کم و بیش
More or less
چرا بهت میگن دست نشانده؟
Why are you called Figurehead?
بخاطر اینکه خشک و زشته
He's called that cause he's wooden and ugly
خیلی پولداره
And money flows by him like water
Get your ass in
در کار نمیکنه
دستت رو روش نگه دار
The door isn't working.
Just keep your hand on it
امنه؟
Is it safe?
You bet, with me at the wheel
it's smooth and safe
حرومزاده
You son of bitch
You're gonna study here, Sis 13?
ببخشید
Excuse me
How much you get out of Atlantic City
just now?
حدود 3000 دلار
About $3000
Touch me $1000 -Again
چه رشته ای میخونی
What do you study?
بازیگری
Acting
مکزیکی های خدا نشناس
Goddamn Mexicans!
What you rushing to hell for?
Watch me and I get you bumped off to Mexico
I'll beat the fucking shit out of you!
دهنتو‌سرویس می‌کنم
اونا یه کلمه از حرفات هم نمی‌فهمن
They don't understand a word you said
تا موقعی که خوشحالم نیازی نیست بفهمن
They don't have to, as long as I'm happy
آره، اهمیتی نداره
Yeah, who cares?
دفعه بعدی میبرم، مطمئنم
Next time I win, I'll sure
buy a goddamn Thunderbird
گورتو گم کن. هیچی پول ندارم
Fuck off! I got no money!
برو برو
Go...go!
هیچتونه شماها؟ گمشید
Hey, what's matter with you? Fuck off
-Get out
No sweaU
یالا
Come on!
سریع راه بیوفت
Quick! Move your ass!
دوباره شانسمون رو امشب امتحان میکنیم
We'll try our luck again tonight
at the gambling den
برو
Go...
امشب میبینمت
See ya tonight
بیا تو
Get in
خودشه؟
This is it?
Right on. Nice, huh?
Come in ...Hi?
Hi -Right
$300 a month, all inclusive
Maintenance, security, everything
There's a pay-phone at the stairwell
Gas and electricity on your own
Here, this fridge is run by gas
Run by gas?
Right you are
You'd better watch out
and keep it properly shut all times
I live right underneath
if you need me just stamp on the floor
You wanna pull down the house!
صبح بخیر.
Good morning
اون چیه؟
What is it?
عذر میخوام
I'm sorry...
برو سر اصل مطلب
Get to the poinU
دوست پسرم امروز به بوستون بر میگرده
My boyfriend is returning from Boston today
میخوام توی ایستگاه ببینمش
I want to meet him at the station
میتونی بهم بگی چجوری خودمو اونجا برسونم؟
Can you show me how to get there?
متروی نیویورک یه هزارتوئه
مردم فرشته نیستن
New York subway is a labyrinth.
People ain't no angels
برای دخترب مثل تو خطرناکه
It's dangerous for a girl like you
آره خیلی خطرناکه
Yeah, very dangerous
درسته
Right, very dangerous
باشه...باشه
Okay.. .okay
I'll go get changed, be right back
Women are chable'!
What'd you say? Chable?
Nuisance! Trouble!
Don't you understand English?
No one ever came to meet me
in my 10 years of sailing career
Vincent doesn't expect me here either
How long it's gonna take?
15 minutes
If you say 15, you mean 30
I ain't wrong to take it for 60, e[i?
How do I look? Give me a grade
A plus
Wait for me
Hurry
Peggy, what do you think of this game?
Well, I think the pitcher is the best
What about me?
Jenny...!
Stop it.
This is embarrassing in front of people
I don't care! Nobody knows me here
Here are the clay dolls you asked me to make
Now don't act like a child
It took me two months to make them.
Don't you want them?
Now that you're here
Have you got a place to stay?
None of your business. What do you care?
When I came or when I will go
Calm down!
Over here girls are liberal-minded
It's just like saying 'Hi'
Saying Hi?
That simple?
Well, what a party? Who is she?
Go ahead, tell heM
Peggy, this is Jennifer, from Hong Kong
Hi
I won't say 'Hi' to her
] en n i fe r...
Let's go. Move it!
Hello, hang on
Call for you
Leave me alone
Might as well give him a good scolding
No...
She wont answer your call
Well, Silver Palace Restaurant then
He wants to see you tomorrow
No
Lost again yesterday, dammit
Excuse me
So?
Well, now that you're here
you should...
widen your horizon
and experience different lifestyles
You mean get to know more girls?
Don't be childish
You should open up more
It took me two years to save up...
enough money to come study with you
I've always encouraged you to further study
But, not necessarily with me
What's more,
I'm planning to transfer to Boston,
I'm leaving tomorrow
With her?
Mind your feet!
I'll see
Tell me
Do you prefer her to me?
You shouldn't tag along all the time
It's no good for your growth
Don't talk like you're doing this for me
Just say you want to leave
What should I say?
Remember what Woody Allen said?
A relationship is like a shark
It has to move constantly. Or it dies
Did Allen Tam the singer say that?
He only said:
What a trap, and why me, why me
Bullshit
Sis 13
Gas leak...!
What's up?
Call the Fire Department!
Are you airight?
You airight? Sis 13?
Fire Department? We got fire here
Get out the house. Where's the leak?
There
Goddammit. Go! Go home!
Hello
What's up?
I don't know. He hung up
The phone didn't even ring
Really?
Wanna go for a walk?
Figgy
how about taking me to Boston?
No, you ain't going, dammit!
You're here to study
Make good use of your time to learn
Forget about that jerk
He doesn't care for you
Who says he doesn't care for me?
It's obvious, come on
Look at yourself. You're mess
Crying your eyes out, tearing yourself apart
You only make yourself cheap
Figgy, I'm already 23
Fantastic,
the prime of your life I'm 33 already
A 23-year-old woman is
older than a 33-year-old-man
Let's get back home
Mammy, I've been here for a week now
Figurehead has found me a nice apartment
Cosy and spacious
New York is beautiful
Vincent has been busy lately but...
we're going to see a musical next week
The school's started
Don't worry about money, I have enough
Don't send me anymore. Save it for yourself
What do you want?
Egg sandwich
How many eggs?
How much are they?
$0.60 for 2 eggs, $0.50 for 1
1 egg
Sandwich, Single egg
Hey, Figgy
Hello, animals. How's it going on?
Sis 13, see ya guys around
What brought you here?
You do know your way around
Single egg sandwich, goody!
Hey, kid, come here
What's up, Figgy?
2 roast duck rice, extra duck.
What's soup of the day?
Winter melon
Get me 2, extra melon. No charge!
Okay, anything you say
Quick
Didn't see you a couple of days
School just started
Good, Washington said,
'A good start is half way to success.'
Did Washington say that?
If not Washington then it must be Confucius.
Either on&
Here, Figgy. Special for you
Yummy yummy
Dig in. Can't study with an empty stomach
A country is as good as its people
and its people as good as their food
Come on, dig in!
Let go yourself
And enjoy
You ain't got too many lives to live
Say, Figgy, where can I buy a bookshelf?
Buy? I'll build one for you
Good, someday when you're free...
A real man doesn't say someday
He says today
Let's go after this
Bath-tub, desk
Too bad that window is blocked off...
or we can see Brooklyn Bridge
It took me 3 days to paint this window.
You dig?
I dig. Soda
Good.
Study hard from now on
Don't let people look down on you
What else can I do now that I'm here
Nice watch
My grandpa gave it to me
Only the watch band is too worn-out
What a pity! Get another one
I don't even have money for my tuition
I found a part-time job, babysitter
How much?
Enough for rent
I need another job...
for the rest
Then I can rest assured and really study
Smart girl. Some ambition
There might even be money left
for a Broadway show
Yankee opera. They're disgusting
Shall we dance...?
Please line up, sir
There are people like this
Sis 13
Here comes your Broadway tickets
What'd you say?
It's for you
Doing your own cooking
Here your fried rice, not salty enough
Looks funny
I'm in a hurry
I start babysitting tonight.
All the way out to Long Island.
Nice area
A girl likes you should be with a good family
Ain't no good to be with scum like me
Going tonight?
Yeah, right now.
What'd you say just now
about Yankee opera tickets?
You got tickets for me?
Hell, Yankee opera is disgusting
It'll taste better...
if you think of it as fried cookies
Close the door for me, please. Bye
I ain't scalping ticket!
I ain't no yellow cow (scalper)
You can't sell tickets out of here!
I'm just waiting for my girlfriend!
Whatever you say is right!
Whatever I say is wrong!
I don't understand what you are talking
You talk all yes talk! I talk all no talk!
Figgy -Right on Sis 13
This dumb cop doesn't even understand English!
Tell him I ain't no yellow cow
You know this guy?
I don't understand you either
Are you his friend?
Yes, these tickets, one for me and one for him
These are ours
Airight! Just take off!
Understand? Not yellow cow
Stupid cop! I ain't no scalper
I ain't got nothing
but I got my dignity
You bought those tickets for me?
Of course not, they're Bull's
Ain't you gonna babysit?
Oh no, I'm late
Where to? Let me drive you there
That junk?
I'm too tired to hold the door on today!
It's a new car
So this is your new car!
You can hear every part except the horn
I had a rough night,
stripped down to the last penny
But this is a good convertible
Same as Reagan's
Look at this hole. I'd better watch my feet
Why don't you quit gambling?
I need it to balance my mind
Come on, we're gonna late!
Let's wait for five more minutes, okay?
We'll be late...
Sorry, I have to run
I'll come after parking the car
You told her what time to come?
Sorry, Mrs. Sherwood
Didn't we say 6:30?
Next time, I'll be...
You'd better. Time is important to me
I wait for you in the car
My daughters in there,
go in and introduce yourself
I have to rush for the show
Bye
Why don't you go in?
Well? Get in...
Hi
Figgy, come in and stay with me for a while
It's just a little girl
Please
Women are chable'!
Hi, Anna, have you eaten? -Yup
Let me introduce
this big fellow here Uncle-Figgy
Hi
You're Piggy
Right
I want some grapes
o kay
Aren't you going to peel them for me?
Nobody peels grapes
You just spit it out afterwards
No. All my babysitters peeled them for me
Shame on you
You're a big girl now, you know
Watch me
See how I eat melon seeds
You see!
You had the melon seeds
in there first Open your mouth
You have bad breath
And you have a big mouth
If you don't behave, I'll beat you up
Fuck it. Stripped clean again!
Hurry up, how come?
Wait!
I got to quit gambling
Touch me $100
Got to quit
Got a cigarette?
I want to start saving and open a restaurant
Nuts! Money is to use, not to save
I'll spend my last penny...
on the day I croak
Hi, Figgy
Snack for you
Thanks. Did you remember Anna's mother?
Sure, the one with 200 boyfriends
One of her boyfriends, a dirty old man...
wants to hire me
as a waitress in his restaurant
Oh, yeah?
You'd better be careful
I'll be fine
You want me to check him out?
No need, really
But come and see me at the restaurant
Ain't got no time
Here, for you
How ugly! Who's this?
Guess
Such an ugly face
Must be me
You're not so ugly
If you shave,
your chin looks like Richard Geres
Really?
Yeah, it looks like his knee
I was a student once
Went through a IoU
Be a good girl and...
I'll raise your pay, okay?
But you said you got no time
I happened to pass by
This is Tony, our manager. This is Figgy
This way
That's the dirty old man
I can see that
Make yourself comfortable
What do you suggest?
How about fired rice?
Sir, this is on the house
What is this?
Fin de Siecle
Thanks
Sir, would you like to order now? -Sure
Ill leave it up to you. Something simple
-Sure
Sir, how do you like these dishes?
Good! Simple and good
Gee, its 6:35 p.m. already!
Thank you
In the forest and meadow far far away
My dear friend, what oh what is on your mind?
While the birds are chirping happily...
Mammys back!
Anna
You're too early
Mum's still at the beauty salon
Can't I come in and wait?
Hello, Jenny
Can't I say hello to Jennifer?
Don't kiss me. Your beard hurts me
Let's go out to the garden -Okay
Make yourself at home
Anna, wait there
Hello
Such a lovely little girl. Fair and pretty
Just like you
You're not feeling well?
I might feel better
if you take your hand off me
You have a sharp tongue
Let's have coffee some time
and have a nice chat
I'll pick you up tomorrow after school, okay?
You don't have to hold my hand...
to invite me for coffee
Come on, I'm not that kind of man
Have you been to Lincoln Centre?
Here comes Mammy
Mammy
Anna, have you been a good girl today?
Yeah, I've been very good today
Peter did a good job on your hair today!
Jennifer, come here for a second
What's it?
Well, Anna's big now
I'm thinking of sending her...
to boarding school
After she's gone...
there'll be nothing much to do here
I understand
Then well start tomorrow, okay?
Still, I'll pay you for this week
It's not necessary. I'm leaving now
Jenny, where are you going?
Mammy, where's she going?
Jenny said you were a bad girl,
she won't look after you
You're lying. I was very good
Jenny was bad, then
Jenny was good too. Jenny...
What's going on? Who's bad?
You!
What do you mean?
Forget it
Wherere we going tonight?
I was really enjoy the Chinese food
Thank you very much
Great. Thank you
Please come again
I'd love to. I'll do it soon
Thank you. Bye
That's the dirty old man who blew Sis 13's job
Sonovabitch! Take this
And this And this! Now go to hell!
You dirty old man
You go to hell!
You go straight to hell!
Stop it! Stop it...
Fucking bastard!
Figgy, stop it!
Now what have I done?
It was no big deal
Don't get smart now
Are you airight?
Pick up the board
Don't bother! Please go!
What do you mean?
Well, you need not come back to work
Goddammit!
It's okay, Figgy!
Okay. Where's my pay?
What?
Give it to her, dammit
Okay, you win!
Let's split
I'm okay. Let's go
Hello
It's me, Jennifer
Anna, why haven't you gone to bed?
I can't sleep. There's a ghost in the house
Nonsense! Where's mammy?
She had a big fight with Uncle Tony
and she went out
Jenny, I'm scared
Silly girl. Go to bed now
Jenny, please sing me a song
Airight!
In the forest and meadow far far away
My dear friend, what oh what is on your mind?
While the birds are chirping
and dancing happily
My dear friend, what oh what is on your mind?
In the forest and meadow far far away
While the birds are chirping
and dancing happily
My dear friend, what oh what is on your mind?
Where there is will, there is way
See, your clay dolls can keep you alive
All yours!
Let's go eat pizza
Okay
Yankee pancake
Disgusting
Wait. Wait, let me take a look!
Hello
May I help you?
May I have a look of this?
Sure
Take this for me, please.
Gorgeous
Matches my watch perfectly.
Right. Why don't you buy it?
Let's see how much it is
No, thanks!
It's airight
Bye
How can a watchband be so expensive?
Yankee tune, no different from Chinese music
Sounds like a Chinese funeral march
Let's go, Figgy
Why should we?
I don't want to see him. Let's go!
Figgy, how do I look today? What grade?
D minus
Be serious
How do I compare with her?
Who's her?
You know, her
The one with Vincent
Which one of us looks better?
How should I know? Go ask Vincent!
Why are you so touchy?
I know I'm not as pretty
Always worrying about looks!
It ain't everything!
It is to Vincent
He prefers her because she's pretty
What do you care?
You dumped him! You dumped the past!
Look at your cross face
You're the ugliest on this street!
You don't have to be so mean...
when I'm sad
Sad? Because you ain't pretty?
How about me then? Should I kill myself?
Your mum really spoiled you rotten
What about you?
Gambling 24 hours a day
Pot calling the kettle black!
Who the hell are you anyway?
Okay! I ain't nobody
I ain't gonna bother you no more!
You ain't 'chable' me no more!
I ain't got nothing...
but I got my dignity
Here I win again!
Figgy
Here, for Iuck
Figgy, spare me $2,000
What for?
Just give it to me
What you need it for?
Forget it
What is it?
Aren't you opening your own restaurant?
Right! And for that restaurant
What's the matter?
I pay the gangs $400 a week
Still not enough
Last week I was tight and...
they smashed my front window yesterday
Fuck it!
We'll get them or my name is not Figgy!
Wait! Where you gonna find those assholes
at this hour?
Forget it, Figgy
If I can help it...
I ain't want to fight & hurt my business
They'd be better not...
mess with us again!
If they do you let me know...
and I'll smash them!
Got ya
One and four
Threes the winner!
No money, no worry. Lets split!
(Dinner Time)
Come in. Dinner's ready
Try my cooking
Have some fish soup. I made it
It's awful!
Really?
To make fish soup, you must add orange peel!
Also, you should use ripe potatoes
And you mustn't put in salt too early
Or the fish wouldn't be tender
Did you use refined salt?
Yes
Big mistake! You must use natural salt
And you mustn't stand too far or too close
You must be two feet away from the pot
2 feet
2 feet?
Right. You don't understand?
Okay. Let me tell you
Sit down and listen
If you're too far, it'll be too bland
If too close, it'll be too salty
I see!
Good. Go ahead
It will be a fine day tomorrow
How do you know? Your rheumatism doesn't hurt?
In October...
if the evening wind is southerly...
the following day will be a fine day
Really? No bullshit?
The observatory may be wrong...
but a sailor is always right
And when there's lightning,
watch where it comes from
East means rain; south means wind
West means sunshine; north means gust
That's what you learned
during those sailing years?
What else was there to do?
All you saw everyday was the sea
and a couple of seagulls
I heard that every seagull
is the soul of a dead sailor...
returning to his homeland
to see his friends
See those fishing over there!
They'reyour sailor friends
Get out of here!
Even if I were dead,
I wouldn't want to be a seagull
Flying all day long is tiring
When I'm dead, I want to just lie there
Flying is great!
I want to see more places
Once I was afraid to travel...
but not anymore
I want to see the world. Don't you?
I've been everywhere in the world
I don't want to go anywhere anymore
What do you want then?
I want to open a restaurant someday right here
Facing the Atlantic Ocean
Every night after work...
I can sit by the door...
enjoy the breeze, drink some beer...
And gamble?
No. No need to balance my mind
if I'm my own boss
Not even if your friends invite you?
No more gambling
And by then my friends will all be gone
Maybe...you'll be gone too
Maybe I'll still be here
Then we can. ..watch the sea together
What will you call your restaurant?
You got suggestions?
Let me think...
Didn't your teacher give you an English name?
Yeah. Samuel, Samuel Pang
Call it Sampan, then
Sampan? The boat?
Right you are
Sampan.. Sounds good
Welcome to Sampan
Table for two? Just a minute, please
Thank you
The ride was real fun
Yeah. Lets go again when we have money
Want some?
Let me sing you a song
In the forest and meadow far far away
My dear friend, what oh what is on your mind?
While Sampan is chirping and dancing happily
My dear Chable'. . . is that how it goes?
You know this song too?
I overheard you
I'm going downstairs
If you need me for anything stamp on the floor
Okay? I'm going.. I'm going
Stamp on the floor!
3 Commandments : Quit gambling,
quit drinking and quit smoking
5 Goals : Diligence is the key to success
Get the Green Card, then the Gold Card!
Wear shoes, wear socks;
speak grammatical English
If you want it, go for it
Sampan wants Chable, Sampan goes for C[iable
Someone wants Chable
Fatty: Since coming to America,
everything has changed
Do you remember the Figurehead?
I think he's in love with me
I feel free when I'm with him
Yet somehow there's a kind of man...
who's fun to be with,
but marriage is something else
We belong to two different worlds
If we should part someday
I don't think either of us could take it
He's over 30...
and this looks like his first love
I had a hard time getting over Vincent
You know.. .a relationship is exhausting
Red is good, goddammit!
Red is romantic
You know shit about colouM
White is pure
White? Yeech! I say red!
I say white! Shut up!
Now what should I choose : red or white?
Okay. Quick -What's up?
Nothing, just cleaning up the yard
Oh, we're having a party here next week
You'll be free?
A party? Of course
Invite your friends too
All of them
Great! I'll do it now
What's the occasion?
Do you need a reason to have fun?
Why didn't you tell her it's your birthday?
Why tell her, as long as I'm happy
Well, it's your birthday
You 'urn luen' her
What's that? You jerk!
He says that you have a crush on her
I know I'm right. You 'urn luen' her!
You're crazy! Now move your ass and work
You guys are coming to the party too, right?
Look. I'll help you decorate...
but I ain't coming to the party
Come on. I'm inviting you guys!
Me neither
I'd rather have my hands on the cards
Ain't we friends?
Forget it!
Step aside! Hot water!
Hello. Please come in
Hi, Jenny
Welcome you
Hi
How are you?
Whose chicken?
Let me...
Sure! Here you go!
Why do you so late?
Excuse me. Can I have a steak?
Sure! Medium rare. Okay?
Thank you
Please get me that one -Wait a minute
Jennifer, you're in another world
She's thinking of her boyfriend
Excuse me
Figgy, lets dance
Dance with your classmates
Come on
Some other day
A real man doesn't say someday
He says today
I guess you're right
Jenny, let's dance
Come on
The next one, maybe
The next one. Promis&
The next one
Do you like the food?
It's great. Jenny
Really, thanks a lot!
Can I have a little rib?
Thanks!
How did you...
-I heard you...
I heard you're throwing a party
so I came to see you
Help yourself to the food, I made them
Try the fish soup
So you learned how to cook
Well, mom is not around
You remember the Portuguese restaurant
that makes very good seafood soup?
And has a chunky Philipino singing...
Three coins in a Fountain...
Yeah, he has a strange voice
Right... Each one seeking happiness...
How've you been?
I broke up with Peggy
How about you?
You.. .have a new boyfriend?
I don't know
I know who he is
$600! All of it!
Didn't you say you're having a party?
It's over
Nineteen! Takes all!
Game over
All cleaned out! No money, no worry!
Figgy
What's up?
Figgy, spare me another $2,000
What? Those assholes again?
Bull, don't be afraid!
It's the second time already!
Who the fucks are these guys?
Shut up All of you
Let's just go and smash them! Move!
Now let's go get my car
Figgy, I don't want to fight...
Let's go!
Open the door!
Quick! Open the goddamn door!
Piggy, wait...
Open up!
Bye, Jenny
Guys, have great fun. See you later
See you
Figgy, where've you been?
I was bored! I was unhappy!
It's you who wanted to have the party
I asked you to dance but you refused
Dance?
I dance like a crab!
I sing like a crow!
Wherere you going?
Nowhere!
Whoever messes with us will get it!
Right?
You're going to fight?
Yeah, so?
We're all experienced fighters
From Shanghai to Hong Kong,
from Hong Kong to New York
We've seen it all! Right?
Right!
Figgy, you've been drinking
Why, is there a law against drinking?
Can I let my buddies down
if they get me drinks?
Dumb broad! Let's go!
Figgy, don't go
Figgy. .where're you going?
Jenny, you are crazy!
See, you two don't get along!
Leave me alone!
My name is Sampan
I'm 34 years old
I am born in November 9
November 9?
Where are they?
Those assholes usually hang around here
Where the hell are they?
Dammit! Where are they?
There!
It's them?
Right!
It's them? -Right
Fucking assholes! How dare you mess with us!
Go get him!
This flower is for you, my dear
Look at the girl over there
I'll be right back
This flower is for you. Have a good day
Thank you -Take care. Bye
Bye
Anna...
Jenny...!
Hi, Mrs Sherwood
Good morning
How about coming back to babysit Anna?
She misses you
That day.. .1 know it's not your fault
Jenny, please come back!
Let me think about it
Why don't you move in with us...
you don't have...
any relatives here anyway
She does! She has a cousin, Piggy
Silly girl! Cousin Figgy went away
Move in with us then
We can live like one family
Come on, ]ennifer
See ya, brothers
See you -Bye bye
Hello, my friend
Hello, young man. I remember you
This
How much? -Eight hundred
One hundred?
No, eight hundred
Come, come
Car. Give you
What's the use of giving me the car?
All give you
Al right...
Thank you!
Bye
Jenny
You're still here
I've decided to stay in New York with you
Stay if you like...
but don't say it's because of me
You choose the place that suits you best
I thought about it clearly.
New York fits me best!
Today you say New York...
tomorrow you'll say Boston
Anyway it doesn't matter. Your family is rich
I won't depend on my family anymore
Could you get me a job?
You, work?
You wont even get enough for your car
Besides, I won't be able to help you
I'm moving to Long Island...
to stay with the family I babysit
You still mad at me?
You know when I first got here alone...
I was confused and running around
Now I want to settle down
But I don't
I didn't sleep last night...
thinking about you
Three people didn't sleep last night!
Let me go and finish packing
Well, let me drive you to Long Island
Airight, I'll go get the rest
Hi, how are you? -Hi, how are you?
I'll wait for you in the car
You're moving?
Yes, I'm moving to Long Island
Oh, Long Island is nice. Very pretty in Autumn
Here's my address.
Come see me when you've time
Okay.. someday
Yes.. someday
Oh, Sis 13. I got something for you
Thanks
Why didn't you tell me...
it was your birthday?
Why tell anyone, as long as I'm happy
Best wishes
Wait, I have something for you too
Happy birthday
Thanks
Bye...
Take care
Anna, you like it here?
Yeah.
Let's spend our summer vacation here. Okay?
Sure, we could sit on the beach and...
enjoy the breeze at night
I used to have a friend
whose dream is just to open a restaurant here.
Facing the Atlantic
And call the restaurant 'Sampan'
Sampan?
Yes, Sampan, Samuel Pang
Like the one over there?
I hope you enjoy the food
Thank you. Bye. You're welcome
Bye...
Table or two?