When I woke up this morning
Tears were rollin'
down my face
When I woke up this morning,
Lord
Tears were rollin'
down my face
I dreamed the
man that I loved
Has another
lover in my place
You forgot you
said you loved me
Swore you'd never
cause me pain
Yes, you forgot you
said you loved me
Swore you'd never
cause me pain
Why you forgettin', baby?
Remember my name
Well, look who's here.
Curry,
you're fifteen minutes late.
Well, I got fifteen
minutes of problems, Ok?
- Hey, whats going on?
- The problem is you're late, smart ass.
Morning, Neil. Morning, Jeff.
- Coffee.
- Coffee black, right?
- I wanna one of those beef potato burritos.
No, I think you'd much
rather have yogourt.
Much better for you.
Here you go, Jeff.
Here you go.
Hey, I hate to break up this coffee
klatch, but we got work to do.
Now, if you don't want to work,
you keep this up, smart ass.
You and funny man follow me out to lot
number nine. Now come on, let's move.
Hello?
Hello? Is anyone there?
If you tried and
failed at trying.
Hear you played
a losing game.
Yes, you tried and
failed at trying.
Hear you played
a losing game.
Ah, if you need a
friend to call on, yes.
Remember my name.
This way, ladies. Oh, I know they're
going to look wonderful on you.
Let's see, this is thirteen.
Yes, can I help you, miss?
Anything you want?
Just looking.
I want it to fit right.
You look wonderful.
Yeah. Does it fit right?
Well, I think maybe you can pull it in
your waist a little bit and show your...
My husband likes me in
loose-fitting clothes.
In that case we have this wonderful
kimono here. Look at the beautiful colours.
That would look great with it, and at night you
can put up your hair. Doesn't that look great?
- That's just lovely.
- I'll take it.
Wonderful.
Will this be cash or charge?
Where did you
get your shoes?
- Oh, downstairs.
- It'll be cash.
Ok, fine.
And wrap it up as a present,
Ok?
When's Matt coming home?
Well, he's on the road a lot.
Hi. You the man around here?
My name's Emily and I
just moved into 20,
and I'm going to have to have a
couple of lamps for my place. Ok?
So, you got a name?
Yeah, Pike.
Well, Mr. Pike,
I love music too.
It's not Mr. Pike, just Pike.
Will you please get
out of my place?
Nice place.
You sure have a lot of stuff.
Come on up some night
Thanks for the lamps, Pike.
you can blow your top
cause everything's free
On the top floor the
third door to the left
That's where you'll
always find me
Stuff is there and the
chicks fell in romp with glee
Don't worry bout a thing cause I'm
layin' it on the line for protection
Tell them cats downtown they
can let their conscience be
Come on up, bring your friends
and we'll start that ball a rollin'
My castles rockin',
run on by and see
I'm layin' it on ya!
You sit down Dad,
it's Ok, I'll get it.
- Hello?
- Honey who is it?
It's Neil.
Look uh.
I think I should stick around here and
talk to Jeff. He's in pretty bad shape.
When do you think
you'll be coming over?
Oh, in about an hour,
an hour and a half.
It's something I just have to do, you know?
I'll be there in less than two hours, Ok?
Ok, bye.
Is Neil coming over?
In a couple of hours.
A couple of hours?
Honey, is there anything
wrong between you and Neil?
I didn't cry when
you disappeared.
I was worried about you.
But I figured that you
had to do your own... shit!
I was worried about you.
But I figured.
Good night.
So, how's Jeff?
Oh, he's Ok, you know. He's Ok.
- Neil?
- Yeah?
Are things all
right with us?
Have you ever noticed, every time you spend time
with your folks that the first kind of questions...
Neil, I want to know if there
are problems between us.
You haven't been
happy in a while.
I got problems in my life
shortcut, but not they're not you.
Hey, you want to go somewhere
and grab a hamburger? Huh?
Evening ladies
and gentleman.
The top story at this hour
is the tremendous earthquake
that hit the city of Budapest,
Hungary earlier today
Almost had it out with Frank's
today. What a first-class jerk.
Hello?
Who is it?
Is that is that the yellow
house on the corner?
Yes, that's right,
who is this?
Is that number 555?
Yes, that's right who's this?
Who you talking to?
Honey, don't be polite with freaks.
Rivalling the Calcutta quake of 1737
which killed nearly half a million people.
Smart guy, he doesn't like TV.
Neil.
It was a woman.
The ancient city of Budapest,
Hungary, was the scene this evening
of what could possibly be the most
violent earthquake in recorded history.
Tremors measuring as high
as 8.6 on the Richter scale
Here you go.
Just coffee and juice, Ok. You
don't have to eat the toast.
Thanks. I'm not real hungry
or anything. I'm on a diet.
You know, you're going
to be late to work.
Ok.
Hey, I got an idea.
Let's go out to dinner
tonight, just you and me.
That little Mexican place, six
courses, a buck seventy-five.
Mom's picking me up, we're going to spend the day
together. Why don't you call me there later on.
Ok, don't say I didn't ask you.
Asshole!
Hey baby, what's life
without an asshole, huh?
After you, sweetheart.
Hi.
What in the hell is it doing
on 11 when it's always.
It belongs on 11.
Oh, shit.
Can I smoke in here?
Yeah.
Want a smoke?
No.
Do you know a Mr. Nudd?
Yeah.
Do you know where he is?
Back there.
Ok.
Seventy-nine? Shhh.
I can get them across the
street for fifty-nine.
Oh, but I like this.
Can I help you?
I'm looking for Mr. Nudd.
Mr. Nudd's not in.
- Cop says he's here.
- Well, he's busy.
I have an appointment.
Is this the way?
That's the way but he's busy.
Well, he's expecting me.
Look, I'm the assistant
manager, can I help you?
See you after Christmas,
after the first of the year.
Mr. Nudd?
Someone to see you.
- I'm Emily.
- Hello, Emily.
Just going to be a minute.
- You on your break Rita?
- Yes.
Have a seat, have a seat.
Did Shirley tell you that I
didn't really need anybody?
Your mother promised me
that you'd have a job for me.
She promised.
Well, I want you to know that I
don't really need anybody here,
but I'll give
you a job anyway.
Now, I have a speech that make
to all of Shirley's friends.
You have a great mother.
Yeah, I know but I
have a speech anyway.
I take you people on, no
questions or discrimination.
You work for me
and we start even.
If I find shortages, cash or merchandise,
and I don't know who it is, I fire you.
That's my policy and that's
the last I'll mention it.
Shirley said they taught you
how to work a cash register.
I can do cash
and credit cards.
Then that's where you start.
Best to learn about anything is
to know how much it costs, right?
- How is she?
- Who?
My mother.
Oh, she's great. She has her own
shower now and no work details.
No work details?
She's not working?
Rita.
Rita, this is Emily.
I just hired her.
Well put her on checkout for a week, see
how she does. Tell Harry to work in the back.
That's no problem. I'm
getting pretty tired of this.
You're a friend of Shirley's,
aren't you?
Shirley's got a
lot of friends.
Somehow, they all
seem to wind up here.
You know, the last one of Shirley's
friends didn't last too long.
Ok, let's go, Harry. Mr. Nudd
wants you in the back for a week.
This ones taking
over your job.
- Hello.
Well, I'm glad there's a
little class up front.
Ok. Thank you, Harry.
This is a cash register.
This is cash.
Keep track of all
your accidents.
- Accidents?
- We don't smoke up front.
Yeah,
like that one you got on.
Oo, I bet you took this job
for the guys, didn't you?
Well, you know, the guys who come
in here don't like girls in uniform.
We don't smoke up front.
Be polite and
get out of my way.
Get out of my way.
Maybe I should tell Mr. Nudd
that you're a trouble maker.
Did I forget my pen?
Here, look, we're probably not...
- Can you get me a butt can?
- Harry?
Ow, fuck! Shit.
Here you go.
Thanks for the ride, girl.
Wanna come in for a while?
Neil and I might get the
Ok for our cabin tonight.
Oh, no thanks.
Oh, your favourite.
Did you steal these?
I told you, this is not stealing.
With the salary we make it's
called getting even. See you, baby.
Gotcha, thanks.
What's wrong, Barbara?
I want to see you.
What happened?
When are you coming home?
It's going to be kind of late tonight, honey,
some guys hate their families, you know.
Yeah. Maybe I'll drive out?
Ok.
What the hell is going on?
Hey, Bar? Bar? Barbara?
What's the matter.
I don't know.
Somebody ripped up my garden.
I found these here and
now my car wont start.
Wait a minute.
You know I took that course
last year in auto mechanics.
Let me see.
I think it's your coil wire.
Try to start it up now, baby.
You ever get this thing where
you just want to kill somebody.
Neil.
Come here,
let me show you something.
- Hi, Jeff.
- Babs.
Dig these.
Oh, Neil.
Oh, Neil, it's gorgeous.
Are we going to have the little
stained-glass window here?
And is this the patio?
Oh, it's just gorgeous, Neil.
It's beautiful.
Really, it's terrific.
Hey, let's go somewhere and
really groove over these things.
I'll follow you.
I love you.
You shouldn't let
me drink so much.
You're not drunk.
Let's get this door
fixed, Honeybunch.
I'll fix it tomorrow.
They're laying brick tomorrow, I
don't have to be at work till noon.
Gallons.
You're not my idea of drunken.
Hey, come here.
Come here!
Get back in the house,
Barbara.
Who was it?
What do you mean, who was it?
I don't know who it was.
You know we don't have any tape
or garbage bags or anything.
Why didn't you tell me
about the garden earlier?
Should we call the police?
I don't want to deal
with the police.
I don't want
anybody to get hurt.
Nobody's getting hurt, Barbara.
What did you do?
Come on.
Nobody's getting hurt, Ok?
I'm worried now, but I
wont be worried long
Hi, can I come in?
I'm going to work.
I'll only stay a few minutes, Ok?
Hey, Pike,
That mirror's really great.
It's exactly what I wanted.
Oh. So,
you've got a girl, hmmm.
I don't bother you.
I expect the same.
I don't want to bother you.
Just wanna be friendly and talk.
I don't talk to nobody.
I listen.
Whats the matter,
you scared of women?
Look,
what do you want from me?
I want a set of clean sheets.
And I want drapes
for my windows.
Want, want, want.
I want my house livable.
You have to make
it livable yourself.
Oh, listen to that.
Isn't that just
typical of a stone cop.
You bulls are all the same. I know what you want.
You want me to beg for favours. Ok, I'll beg.
Look.
Clean sheets.
Gimme clean sheets.
Drapes.
Clean sheets.
Drapes for my windows.
Gimme drapes.
Don't you dare kiss me!
Hold me.
Takes a woman to take
a man out of himself.
But to do that, she's got
to be better than him.
What are you looking for?
Harry?
- Do you want me to have a handkerchief?
- Yeah.
No, not necessarily.
I don't like your attitude,
Harry.
Forgot the
dish-washing liquid.
Oh, she told you,
it's Rita's fault.
You know,
I could call in sick today.
No, you don't have to. Teresa's
going to come by and see me later.
Really? Will she stay?
I don't know but it
doesnt matter, I'll be Ok.
Really, don't worry about me.
How's it going, sweetheart?
I missed you punching out.
Is that your wheels?
Yeah, this is them.
You gonna give me a ride?
Sure, hop on.
Ok.
- Hey, Emily, I want to give you a little advice.
- You smell nice.
Oh, thank you,
that's my private stash.
Feel nice too.
That's cause I'm
such a nice guy.
Look I been around here long enough to
know what I'm talking about all right?
- If I were you...
- Can I have a hit?
Look, if I were you, I wouldn't trust Rita
as far as I could throw her, all right?
How come?
Because she keeps spreading
these stories about you.
Good stories or bad stories?
Well, some shit about
you being in jail.
It was garbage, right?
I know, it's cool if you were.
Fuck me, Rita said that?
Yeah, Rita said it the other
day. How long were you in for?
Well, Rita's lying.
I've never been in jail.
That's what I figured.
She's got some problems.
It's horse shit.
Let's hit it.
- Hang on tight, all right?
- All right.
Hey, Emily!
Some other time, Harry.
Hi.
Rita in there?
Yeah.
Getting ready for a meeting.
Old Nudd asked me to
give her a message.
You remember me, don't you?
You scared me.
Does that turn you on?
Maybe.
Wait! What the hell?
I was never in prison.
That was somebody else.
Snitch!
Well, yeah, you were down sixteen dollars
yesterday but I didn't say anything.
Don't you ever spread
lies about me again.
Bye, bye.
Baby, you all right?
Get your ass movin', we're late.
Pike.
Could you get me a security
lock for the front door?
You wanna keep people out
or you want to stay in?
Well, I just don't want
anyone to steal my stuff.
Now you don't want something.
Lot of these chicks
keep crying murder
Me, I don't have
to move my hand
Yes, let these chicks
keep crying hard luck
Me, I don't have to move my hand
I got myself a
little apartment
Dog and a cat
and a working man
He'd never win no
beauty contest
Goodness knows he
don't dress fine
I said he'd never win
no beauty contest
Goodness knows he
don't dress fine
Gimme a beer, Ok?
Not allowed to sell them.
Ah,
but he's healthy and ambitious
And he lays it on the line
I'm getting outta here.
I don't want no hepster lover
They've got larceny
in their eyes
I don't want no hepster lover
Hey, Neil, check this out.
Say, I think I'm in love!
Too slick for that jive!
Got a hand full of gimme
and a mouth full
of much obliged
Ah but when people
see us out together
They kind of laugh
and turn away
Kind of sneer and turn away
Ah, but the joke
is on them baby
Cause I'm eating three
square meals everyday
All right, chicks, stop crying
murder if you'd just adopt my plan
Yes, you glamour girls
can stop crying inflation
If you'd just adopt my plan
Stop letting these
hepsters jive you
Get yourself a working man
Dry martini, please.
Sure, at the bar.
Oh, I'm waiting for someone.
Right. At the bar.
Ok.
- This one here is real pretty also.
- You like?
Sorry, not interested.
- Ladies.
- Bye, Larry.
In the oven at 350,
stick in the cloves.
Who are you?
What do you want?
You just get out
of here right now.
I'm going to call the police.
So, you got a name?
My husband will
be home any second.
Neil?
This for you?
Barbara.
How do you know my name?
- How do you know Neil?
- How do you know my name?
How do you know, Neil?
Butterfly.
Pop the tomato, you spend twelve
years cleaning up the mess.
Are you a good fuck?
Yes, you're a good fuck.
And a good cook.
Neil's wife.
Where do you know Neil from?
I met Neil in the
back of a crowded car.
He must have been
about 12 years old then.
How'd it go today?
I said how'd it go today.
Nothing happened.
what did you see today and
what are people talking about?
Well, Arlene,
today I saw faces.
Yet I saw violence
on those faces.
Today, people are
talking about themselves.
It's that time of year when a family likes
to snuggle together before a cozy fire
and anticipate the holidays.
When a man likes to
light up a good cigar
or open a beer
before the next game.
The woman window shops
for just the right scarf
to go under that winter coat
that's been in mothballs all year.
I saw young lovers arguing,
then making up.
And I saw a traffic officer
warning, instead of ticketing.
It's that time of year when one
needs to escape within himself
and forget the problems of the
past and plan for the future.
You know, Arlene,
I think that may be the reason no one
is talking about the Budapest earthquake...
They don't understand it
Gee,
but it's hard to love someone
When that someone
don't love you
I'm so disgusted
Heartbroken too
I got the downhearted blues
Once I was crazy about a man
He mistreated
me all the time
Next man I get got to
promise to be mine, all mine
Lord he mistreated me
He drove me from his door
Dirty dog
Yes, he mistreated me
Oh, he drove me from his door
Ah but the good book says, you
got to reap just what you sow
Guess who I saw tonight?
Neil.
And as soon as
he saw me I ran.
And he followed me.
I ran to the beach...
...and I fell in the sand.
He held me.
You've been short every day since
you started. 86 dollars in all.
Rita didn't tell me for three days, I almost
fired her too, but you're through as of right now.
- I didn't steal any money
- I didn't say stole it.
You're just short and
I won't discuss it.
- Mr. Nudd, I want to speak to you alone
- No.
Rita, get back to work.
Close the door Rita,
will ya?
I don't want to hear
any stories, Emily.
I get all the stories
I need from my mother.
You people are lucky I have
a soft spot in my own family.
I did not take any money and
I did not make any mistakes.
Argue with the adding
machine too, that's it.
It wasn't my fault.
I don't have to hear any of this. I warned you
right in the beginning about all everything.
Mr. Nudd, you're going to have your money
back in the cash register tomorrow night.
- That's not the point.
- I promise.
The point is that I'm innocent
and you're saying I'm guilty.
Because of
circumstantial evidence.
And because you're a bigot.
- Bigot my ass. I hired you in the first place,
lady - Did your mother ever tell you how she did it?
- Please, put that down.
- Did she ever tell you how she did it?
- Oh, it was very nasty.
- Listen you don't know what I've been through.
You don't know what it's like to have
a mother who killed your own father.
- Get out of here right now.
- Get your hands off me!
And listen you're going to get your god damn
money back here whether you like it or not!
Tomorrow night it's going to be right there!
I don't give a shit whether you fire me or not.
Prick!
Stay through tomorrow.
But not at the register,
in back with Harry.
Thank you, Mr. Nudd.
86 bucks in Nudd's office
tomorrow morning, Rita.
Hey, Rita, what's happening?
I'm gonna kill that bitch!
Oh, bye, bye, sweetie, I'll see
you tomorrow, don't forget.
How you doin'?
You gonna scare me again?
Look baby, I'm gonna do a
hell of a lot more than.
Goddamn son of a bitch!
- Mr. Nudd?
- Yeah?
Hi I'm Barbara Curry,
I shop here all the time.
- Yeah, I know you, we've met.
- Do you have a girl who works.
I just saw, I just
saw something, I...
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine. Could I make a phone call?
Meanwhile the grim task of
searching for bodies continues.
Primarily in the fifth and
eighth districts of the city.
The areas of densest population
and tallest buildings.
Pacific News Overseas reports that the
official death count now stands at 725,000.
I'm not sure it's her now. It was a
long time ago. She was blonde then.
Why don't you call the cops,
man?
When's the last time
you called a cop?
Hey listen, if you need some
heads busted let me know.
That's good. Thank you.
See you later, Neil!
Hey, let's...
- Hi, Pike.
- Hi.
Thanks for the curtains.
Did you remember
the security locks?
I like that.
California veneer.
That ought to keep them out.
Do you live here?
What's your name?
- Five seven...
- That's her. - Blue dress.
- You're under arrest.
- It was only a pencil.
Pencil? It takes more than a
pencil to break a window, lady.
Break.
Pike!
Hey, Emily!
Bye.
Gone, just like that.
- This is a one-way mirror. I want you to
take your time and see if... - Yeah, that's her.
Neil, that's her.
Are you sure, Mrs. Curry?
Yes. I'm positive.
Do you want to file charges?
Yes, I do.
All right, why don't you
come outside with me then.
Mr. Curry?
- Come right over here, please.
- Neil, who is she?
Look, Barbara, it turns out that
this is someone I used know.
And I had no idea that she
was in town and that is.
Bernice, I need a
forms for a 415 booking.
That was changed
to 419 last March.
Yeah, they're always
changing something.
Ok, I want ten of those.
Look, I want to explain this whole
thing to you, but it's just complicated.
and it's just stupid to
get involved with the cops.
Neil,
I'm having her put in prison!
I want you to
know everything!
Mrs. Curry,
I need you over here a minute.
Now what? I want ten of these?
And this is the first one?
- Right, the second - Which
one of these goes first?
Excuse-me... officer.
Bottom line,
it goes like this:
I cant press charges against this woman unless
I have a chance to talk to her by myself.
Could you, could you arrange that?
Because that would be the best thing.
It just would...
Wait over there
by that table.
Hi.
Ok, let's keep this
short and sweet, Emily.
You cannot go around scaring the
shit out of us, you understand that?
I can't have that,
so just get that straight.
Ok?
Nobody's getting hurt.
I only hurt people by
accident, remember?
Hey, Spidermonkey.
Look at your hair. It's grey.
Yeah.
And your face.
You've really been through it,
huh?
Well, I guess you've been
through it too, haven't you?
But you look pretty good.
Yeah, you look good.
I didn't recognize
you with dark hair.
But you look healthy
and alive, it's great.
You look healthy
and alive too.
Ok.
Spidermonkey,
I wrote this speech.
- It's to you, do you want to hear it?
- Well, let me tell you, I'm not really into speeches.
I've got my wife waiting outside and
I'd like to take her home, so... not really.
Please?
Ok, look, you sit over
here and I'll sit over here,
and we'll kind of observe the
amenities of this institution.
Go ahead, what is it?
Ok.
I didn't cry when
you disappeared.
Hold it! I had my
reasons for moving away.
I had my reasons for
getting married again.
I thought everything out
and I came up with reasons.
- And, believe it or not, I understand
how you feel, Emily - Hold me.
- Hold you?
- Hold me.
- Hold me. Please.
- No.
No.
Oh I get it, you don't want
to hold a convict bitch, huh?
- Drugged and raped and dirty...
- Hey, what do you want from me?
You cant tear out my soul because
I've already done that myself.
Ok?
Ok.
Hold me.
Listen.
I didn't cry when
you disappeared.
I was very worried about you.
But I figured that you
had to do your own time.
And I understood that.
Do you really want to know what kept
me alive during those 4,380 days?
Ghosts.
And one in particular. Yours.
You were with
me all the time.
And when I looked at people, pretty soon came a
time when I could only see the landscape behind.
But when I looked for you,
you were there.
with your face and your eyes.
and your hands.
And you came to me.
and you talked me in that
deep sexy voice of yours.
And you did wonderful
things with me.
Things we used
to be shy about.
You love me, Neil.
I'm the most important thing in your
life, remember you told me that.
Remember?
Just one more thing, Neil.
I want you to know.
You're the very first person
that's held me in 12 years.
I saved it for you.
Hold me.
Ok, we've finished now.
Listen.
I have enough money to keep us
going till you get started again.
And there's enough room at
my place for both of us.
My address is in your pocket.
So, I'll just wait for you to call.
I don't think we're going to be pressing
those charges. You know what I mean?
My wife...
My other wife.
Hey, thank you.
Thank you for your...
Ok, Shortpie, let's go!
Who is she, Neil?
I told you who she was.
- She's someone I used to - They said
she was an ex-convict! Who is she?
I used to be married to her.
You liar!
When were you
married to her?
It was a long time ago. It was New York
City. It's got nothing to do with us.
- Why didn't you tell me this before, you liar?
- God damn it, Barbara, will you come on?
- Emily?
- Hi.
Why'd the cops take you away?
Just an accident.
Why don't mind your
own fucking business?
Hey, hey, hey,
look what I got for you.
I noticed you've been
acting very strange dear
You've never treated
me this way dear
Who the hell put
that thing in here?
You say you've
found somebody else
Emily!
I can help you, Emily.
Afraid you can't help.
Oh, I know how it is when
you're in trouble with the cops.
I got some money saved, hundred and
twenty, hundred and thirty dollars.
You can pay me back when
things are right for you.
Look, I'll tell you what.
I'll put anything in
your apartment you want.
Emily?
Ok.
Good.
- Why cant you just trust me?
- I've trusted you all along!
- I know but have I ever let you down?
- Neil, this woman is dangerous and you're protecting her.
That policeman said she was a
murderer, why are you protecting her?
- She's not a murderer. There was any murder involved.
- Then why did she go to prison?
It was an accident.
The girl went to prison because
the whole thing looked like murder.
Well, I want to know why
it looked like murder.
You want to know a hell
of a lot, don't you?
When I was married to her, things didn't work
out as well as they work out between you and me.
I was having an affair with the girl at
the office that everybody else was having.
This girl got hit by the car.
- You know, you ask me to, to listen
to this story... - It only get's worse.
- and I think you could do me the decency to listen to this story!
- by her lying husband but I'm not hanging around to find out.
- You know, you're being stupid about this, Barba.
- Just let go of me, dammit!
- You know, I happen to have sympathy for this girl.
- Well, that's more than you feel for me!
You really think so?
I feel a love for you
Neil! Let go of me!
don't forget, baby,
what I'm trying to say
It's your time now
Aw, but it's going to be mine
some sweet day
And the cold winds do blow
proceeds set aside for
those quake victims.
The Association urges Non-Hungarian
restaurants to join in their cause.
Northridge.
A Cal State Northridge sociology
professor has published a report
claiming that repression and not depression
is primarily responsible for violent crimes,
and that there is a direct link between
repression and chemical additives used in foods
Hey, Frankie?
This check looks a
little thin to me.
- I docked you thirty bucks.
- What for?
Fifteen for being late. And
fifteen for being a smart ass.
Well, as I see that's
fifteen you owe me.
As I see it,
I don't owe you anything, pal.
- Let's talk about this, Ok? - We're not talking about
anything, you got that? We're through.
You get out of here, I don't want to
see your face around here no more.
Hey, stay there.
Hey, let's go somewhere and
grab a drink, what do you say?
Only if we go
to a nice place.
Yeah? I don't know any
nice places anymore.
But I would just like to sit down
and have a drink with you.
I mean, you and I should be able
to do that, don't you think?
Ok, let's go.
And I'm not going to apologize
for the years, Emily.
I figure you'll square that in
your own distinct way.
But I do think you and I
ought to be able to
just sit down and have a
drink together, huh?
- I have all the good parts underlined.
- I just can't believe that.
If you want to borrow it,
you're welcome.
Yes, I would like two
double extra dry martinis.
At the bar.
Well, I'm waiting for someone.
You want a drink, at the bar.
You want to eat, in the booth.
So, we'll eat.
All right, would you like a
cocktail before dinner sir?
Yeah, two beers.
Two beers.
- Two beers, Mike.
- Two beers coming up.
Want a smoke?
No, I gave up smoking.
- You quit smoking?  - I quit smoking.
I still bite my nails, but I quit smoking.
Wow. Let's see. Oh dear, yes.
- If you had someone to take care of you,
you wouldn't bite your nails. - Two beers.
You forgot the two double
dry martinis, extra dry.
Yes, ma'am.
What dry martinis?
You used to drink martinis,
we used to drink martinis.
I used to do a lot of things.
Do you remember when we
used to go Rockefeller Plaza.
And you used to order
martinis extra extra dry?
Sure, I remember that.
And do you remember how we used to sit watch the
funny man play his drumsticks on the sidewalk?
Yeah, I remember that too.
Do you?
- Do you remember the name of the place?
- Two double dry martinis.
Max's.
Would you like to
look at the menu, sir?
Yeah, show me the drink list.
List...
You want to start at the bottom
of this thing and work up?
Two zombies.
Two zombies...
- So, to Max's
- To Max's.
- Two zombies, Mike.
- Two zombies, coming up.
- I don't know what you're trying to do but I...
- I'm not trying to do anything.
It's doing it'self. Look.
See how it's doing itself?
- Come on, Emily.
- See?
Just ground rules.
Would you like to order now, sir?
Yes.
Two...
Screwdrivers.
Double screwdrivers.
- Two double screwdrivers.
- Listen, we're falling behind here.
Oh, blech! That is horrible!
They make a poor zombie here.
Stay with the martinis.
I gonna get rid of
those two assholes.
How are you?
You know what I mean by that?
- How are I?
- Yeah, how are you living?
I'm really just
the same as before.
- I smoke clove cigarettes.
- Two double Manhattans.
and I still wear
my wedding ring.
But hey. Hey!
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
Well, I'm just sitting here having
a few drinks with my ex-wife.
fifty-five tax, two-fifty each, cover charge for the use
of the booth, that comes to fifty dollars and thirty cents.
How you fixed for money?
Oo, boy, I got money.
Well, I'm really glad to hear that lady because
I'm gonna need fifty dollars and thirty cents.
I bet I have more
money than you.
You have more money than me?
Oh man, I have about ten thousand times
more money than you. Let's see your money.
I'll make you a bet. If I
have more money than you...
If you.
You get to pay the bill.
And I get to take you home.
Fair bet?
Here we have twenty, forty.
- Forty-five, and...
- We got it.
And fifty-nine,
I always carry on me.
- Let's see your money, Neil.
- Is that it?
- Let's see your money.
- No, I got a more.
I got a hundred in here.
Shit!
- I'd like to see some change out of this.
- Hold it!
I got eighty-six bucks,
twenty,
forty, sixty,
eighty, eighty-five.
Eighty-six,
count that up, so...
I win, you get to
pay the bill, and...
You get to come home with me.
Here you go.
- So, you pay?
- I pay.
And I get to come
home with you.
- And I take you home.
- So, as I see it...
I win.
Yeah, you sure do.
My friend left with this dog.
That dog can talk.
Had me a dog that
can talk for years.
When you feel something...
like that.
You don't push yourself.
Maybe optional for some,
but it ain't optional to me.
I can't stand that stuff.
Some people...
I got a visit around here that
carried 3000 at that time.
I don't want to go.
That's the main thing.
How's it going, it's a
beautiful evening isn't it?
Well, you know how it goes.
Nobody knows.
If you had any sense,
you'd do it.
God, I do know.
I got to say this.
You and I...
really...
Really fucked each
others lives up.
But I want to shake your hand
anyway and say that it's okay.
Is that loud enough?
I just got to
get you up there.
My cabin plans.
I'm going to build this
cabin up in eagle rock.
Eagle Rock.
Oh, shit!
Do you know the best
thing about eagles?
- You Ok?
- Yeah.
- You gonna barf?
- No.
You sure?
Yeah,
but don't say that anyway.
Ok. You want some music?
I'll put on some music.
Remember?
Spidermonkey?
Spidermonkey.
You awake?
- You want some coffee?
- No.
Honestly just get me some
club soda and a cold towel.
I'll get you some coffee.
Go ahead, God.
Do it.
The love I have for you
Makes my blue days bright
Asleep or awake, dear
Your face I see
The sunshine of your smile
Is a guide for me
The love I have for you
Is within my heart
No, it feels good, really.
is a thing set apart
You can search
this big wide world
But my dear if you do
You'll never find a love like
the love I have for you
The love I have for you
Makes my burdens light
Makes my blue days bright
Asleep or awake dear
Your face I see
The sunshine of your smile
Is a guide for me
The love I have for you
Is within my heart
Is a thing set apart
If you search this universe
My dear, if you do
You'll never find a love like
The love I have for you
Oh, Pike. Hi.
How'd you like the
stuff I got you?
I love it.
I got you a work lamp too.
Hey, Emily...
Tonight's my night off.
Gotta work.
What are you doin' here?
- What?
- I said, what are you doin' here?
What the fuck does it
look like I'm doin' here?
She owes me a hundred
and thirty dollars.
And you can put this
fucking lamp up yourself!
That's over six hundred dollars
so far. Hope she can pay for it.
Why,
it looks wonderful on you.
Yes, I'll take it. And I'll take the
sweater with it, and I'll wear it.
Fine. Oh, your husband
is just going to adore it.
And I'd like to
take this one.
Ok?
Now, how much does
that all come to?
Well, let's see, with this last one it's, uh,
six hundred and ninety-two dollars plus tax.
Will that be cash or charge?
- Oh, you take credit cards?
- Yes.
Thank you, Mrs. Curry.
Would you like us
to box this one too?
No, that one never fit right.
- Why are you changing all your locks?
- It's none of your business.
Yeah, well, but, if you want to
keep someone out of your house,
all you have to do is change
the combinations on your locks.
Listen, I want a whole bunch
of new locks in this house.
And if you cant do it, I'll
get someone else to do it.
Hey, I can do it. Let me go
get some shit out of my truck.
Jeez.
The bitches I
work for every day.
One indiscriminate turning
of the restless planet.
A planet perhaps that has become
too tolerant of man's inhumanity,
man's disregard,
man's selfish and destructive
attitude toward himself and nature.
When one thinks of one million innocent
victims who died randomly in time,
one cant help but reflect
on his own searches,
his own struggles,
his own randomness.
One million dead,
and certainly more when
the final count is tallied.
But there will always
be more deaths,
and it becomes us, the survivors, who must
accept the responsibility of the future.
Who must move on with the strength and
courage and goodwill of the fallen,
to live the better life.
To live out our potential
as soulful human beings.
I think we can do it.
Take these keys. I want you
to lock up my place, Pike.
Hey, who's that guy upstairs?
Hey Emily!
Yes, you can take every advantage
of a fellow man that's down
You can take somebody's heartstrings,
yes and drag it on the ground
You can high hat other people
just because you're having luck
Even double cross your best friend
and then try to pass the buck
Ah, but there's one thing that is
certain, makes no difference where you go
Just before your final curtain,
you got to reap just what you sow
You got to reap
just what you sow
Yes, you got to reap
The love I have for you
Makes my burdens light
Makes my blue days bright
Asleep or awake dear
Your face I see
The sunshine of your smile
Is a guide for me
The love I have for you
Is within my heart
Is a thing set apart
If you search this universe
My dear if you do
You'll never find a love like
The love I have for you