Transcription by Johannes Grenzfurthner [monochrom.at]
as part of an artistic research program on UK colonial history;
(please help improve this version 1.0)
برخیزید ای جوانان انقلابی مسلح شوید تا من
Come all you young rebels enlist while
برایتان بخوانم از عشق به وطن
I sing for love of one’s
که خانمان سوز است
country is a terrible thing
ترس را به سرعت شعله ای دور می کند
It banishes fear with
the speed of a flame
و همه ی مارا بخشی از جانبازی برای وطن می کند
And makes us all part of the patriot game
نامم اوهانلون است
بتازگی شانزده ساله شدم
My name is O’Hanlon,
I’ve just gone sixteen
خانه ام در موناقان است
جایی در آن بزرگ شده ام
My home is in Monaghan
and where I was weaned
در تمام زندگی لعنت کردنِ
انگلیس ستمگر را آموخته ام
I was taught all my life
cruel England to blame
و حالا نقشی در این انقلاب دارم
And so I am a part  of the patriot game
به سختی دو سال شده
Just barely two years since
از زمانی که با جنگی محلی
I wandered away
از ارتش (آزادی خواه ایرلند) دور شدم
With a local battalion of the bold IRA
درباره قهرمانان وطن می‌خواندم و
میخواستم مانند آنها باشم
I read of our heroes and wanted the same
تا نقشم را در این انقلاب ایفا کنم
to play out my part in the patriot game
آنها به من گفتند
چگونه کانلی کشته شد
They told me how Connolly
was shot in the chair
از زخم هایش آشکارا خون می ریخت
His wounds from the battle
all bleeding and bare
آن قد و قامت رعنا در هم رفته بود و
مورد ضرب و شتم قرار گرفته بود
His fine body twisted,
all battered and lame
They soon made him part
of the patriot game.
-The offensive against
Warrenpoint Harbour, they have
warned the owners of condo
ships using the port
that the safety of their vessels
can no longer be assured.
The harbour has come under motor gun
attack in part because Provisionals
say it’s being used by the army
and marines on intelligence gathering.
Train services between
County Down and Down Cork
have been disrupted
because of a bomb scare.
All the section of the lines and farms,
security forces are searching the area.
-A soldier is still ill after being shot
inside the Royal Victoria
Hospital, in Belfast.
He was hit three times when
a gunman opened fire on him
in a corridor leading from
the casualty department to the canteen.
A policeman was also injured when gunmen
ambushed an ISE Landrover
on Springfield Road.
Several shots hit the vehicle and [?]
-Belfast, North of Ireland,
a summer day like any other.
Since 1970, the days have been filled with
a war that has cost the British government
several hundreds of millions of pounds
and over 600 dead soldiers and police.
In the same time, over 2,000
Irish civilians have been killed.
All this is normally reported
in the news media like the sports scores;
Three Catholics killed, one Protestant
killed, two British soldiers killed.
Terrorists, Protestants, and Catholics
are the words one most often hears.
The image is a bit confused
but they stay nonetheless;
some kind of bizarre religious war.
And yet the two principal forces involved
in the fighting, the British Army
and the Irish Republican Army, have
nothing at all to do with religion.
[music]
-Is that good?
-We cannot indeed afford to have
the country led by any other
policy other than a paramount
ideal of keeping indeed Northern
Ireland an integral part
of, the United Kingdom.
Otherwise, we perish.
As I have previously said, ladies
and gentlemen from this platform,
we the Unionist Party and indeed
the Orange Institution have nothing
to be apologetic for in the treatment
of the minority in this country.
[chanting]
-The city of Derry, October 5th, 1968.
The beginning of,
the civil rights movement.
[crowd screaming]
-These are images of one of the first
civil rights marches in Northern Ireland.
Civil rights, the name
and the tactics immediately
rocked the Southern United
States in the 1950s and ‘60s
in more ways than one,
as is plain to see.
A non-violent form of protest
for moderate reforms
which is met by systematic
police violence.
Only in this time and in this place
the protesters were White.
They were Irish. For most people
who know little about Ireland
and even less about
Northern Ireland, the events
of the late ‘60s are completely
baffling and with a good
reason, for Northern Ireland
is indeed a peculiar state.
For over 50 years, one political
party, the Unionists, were in power.
They had the support of Loyalists of all
social classes thanks to a political
line that was very simple, "Maintain
union with England and preserve
Loyalist supremacy, no
matter what the cost."
This meant control of all
the levels of government;
the police, the courts, housing, as well
as the major sources of employment.
In 1968, unemployment
in the Nationalist community
was nearly 25% compared
to 6% for the Loyalists.
Then there was a special powers act.
Over the years this law
has been used to imprison
thousands of Nationalists
without charges or trials.
To understand all this one must go back
in time to the roots of the trouble.
In 1601, English troops
led by Lord Mountjoy,
defeated the last
of the Irish chieftains.
Ireland, one of the richest
agricultural countries
in Europe was in the process
of becoming a British colony.
In the North of Ireland, where
resistance to the conquest had been
the strongest, large numbers
of Scottish settlers were given land
that had been forcibly
taken from the natives.
The colonizers happened to be Protestants,
displaced Irish happened to be Catholic.
That 17th-century settlement
explains why today in all of Ireland
there are one million Loyalists,
loyal to England that is,
to 3.5 million Irish Nationalists.
300 years later, the Loyalist
produced one of their most
charismatic and extreme leaders,
the Reverend, Ian Paisley.
In the late 60s, Paisley led a popular
Loyalist reaction against the civil
rights movement making it impossible
for the Unionist government,
to offer the Nationalists
even the slightest reforms.
[clapping]
-I am giving a solemn declaration
to you that if there is an election
-In the near future at Oxford,
whether in prison or out of prison,
I’m going to fight on knees and hands.
[cheers] [protestors chanting]
-In the face of Paisley attacks,
the civil rights movement
tried desperately to overcome
traditional sectarian divisions
between Loyalists and Nationalists.
-Today when nearly two and a half
thousand people are unemployed.
-The theory was to ignore
the national question, the division
of Ireland, and instead just call
for social reforms that could
have benefited many
Loyalist workers as well.
The movement’s most eloquent leader
was a young student, Bernadette Devlin.
-Because if he stands up
on his two feet and he says, "Look,
I do 40 hours a week and you make
a great deal of profit
out of my labor and I am
entitled to a better
wage, it is a very simple,
very liberal demand.
I am entitled to more
money for the work I do."
Yet that person, if he make such
a demand, can be fired immediately
because there are two and a half
thousand people wanting that one job.
-The civil rights movement
was not the first effort
to unite the two communities in Ireland.
[music]
-In the 1790s, the United Irish-Men
movement led by protestant
revolutionaries such a Henry Joy
McCracken, organized a major rebellion.
The movement which objected to trade
restrictions imposed by England
was strongly influenced by the American
and French revolutions and aimed
to establish an independent
Irish republic.
Although the leaders of the rising
were mainly protestant
and tried to recruit
settlers into the movement,
the settler community as a whole
stood loyal to the colonial government
and loyal it has remained throughout
every single rebellion in Irish history.
In the 1798 rebellion, 30,000
Nationalists were killed
and over 10,000 Loyalists
died fighting for the English.
[music]
-I would lay a pound
to a penny that England,
like any other time is a slum landlord.
I would lay a pound to a penny
that England, like any other time has got
a rich pasture of land that is
used solely for Yankees to play on.
I would-- [cheers]
-I would lay a pound to a penny that there
are quite a lot of families in Ireland
paying rent they can’t afford for property
they shouldn’t be asked to live in.
That there are people
in this town working
for wages they can’t
keep their family on from
men who don’t need half the money they’re
earning out of the work of Irish people.
[cheers]
-The greatest help that you can
give the people in the North is
by showing the people
in the North that they’re not mad.
They’re not mad for believing.
They’re not mad for being idealist.
They’re not mad for thinking
that someday somehow
we are going to achieve
the workers’ republic.
Where o, where is our James Connolly?
Where o, where is that great gallant man?
He’s gone to organize the union
that working men they might yet be free.
And who, and who will lead the--
-In the early years of the 20th
century, Jim Larkin and James Connolly
organized the Irish working class
and linked it for the first time
to the long-standing republican movement.
This was a revolutionary
development and it led
to the most important of all
rebellions, the Easter Rising.
On April 24th, 1916, Connolly led
the Irish Republican Army, the IRA,
in an insurrection
in Dublin but the rebels,
besides being poorly organized,
had little popular support and within
a week the rebellion had been crushed.
Then the British government blundered.
16 rebel leaders, including
Connolly, were executed and thousands
of Nationalists were interned
in prison camps in England.
Almost overnight, the Irish people began
to give their active support to the IRA.
‘Twas better to die ‘neath an Irish
sky than at Suvla or Sud-El-Bar.
When from the plains of Royal Meath
strong men came hurrying through.
While Brittania’s sons
with their long-range
guns sailed in by the foggy dew.
‘Twas England bade our wild geese go,
that small nations might be free Their
lonely graves are by Suvla’s waves
on the fringe of the grey North Sea.
Oh, had they died by Pearse’s side
or fought with Valera true
Their graves we’d keep
where the Fenians sleep,
‘neath the hills of the foggy dew.
-By 1920, the IRA had developed
a highly successful campaign
that was to become a model
of modern guerilla warfare.
Despite mass arrests,
Britain was unable to defeat
the Nationalists
militarily and the British
government was forced to concede a certain
measure of independence for the Irish.
At the same time, they readily
accepted the demands of the Loyalists
in the North, not to be included
in an independent Ireland.
Thus, a 26 county free state
was formed in the South while
6 counties in the North remained
under British jurisdiction.
The new state of Northern
Ireland was assured a majority
of 1 million Loyalists
to a half-million Nationalists.
The selected six counties
also happened to contain most
of Ireland’s industry but it was
only after a bitter civil war among
republicans before conservative
Nationalists, backed
by the British, were finally
able to impose the settlement.
It was in this way that British
economic interests were
protected, the IRA neutralized,
and Ireland was divided,
and for the next 50 years, the Unionists
in the North governed through
discrimination and Police terror
but the Loyalists were living in fear,
haunted by the specter of the IRA.
The patriot game was far from over.
[dramatic sound]
-Derry city, the end
of the civil rights movement.
[gunshots]
-Beginning August 12th, 1969,
the paramilitary Loyalist police
force attacked the Nationalist
ghettos in Derry and Belfast.
It was reaction in its purest form.
A violent effort
to return to a time before
the civil rights movement had existed
when Nationalists had been
passive and demoralized.
In Derry, barricades in Molotov cocktails
stopped the police, but in Belfast,
the ghettos are smaller and more isolated
and there the police were not stopped.
500 homes in Nationalist
districts were burnt down,
nine people killed and over
1,800 families fled South.
---property in the Belfast area
has been in the Catholic area but it is
the Catholic community which
has suffered most critical damage here.
-Well, this may well be.
I’m not in a position
to say yet because quite
frankly, it hasn’t been
feasible for many people to go
into those areas as you know
and it will obviously
take a very long time to make
a count and assessment
of all the dreadful
things that have happened.
Walls of red-bricked
houses, solace, jarred,
and burned Stand face
to face and back to back.
There is no lace curtains now.
An echo from the distant past
impervious to pain Cement
and bricks and human skill
will raise them up again.
From my flat above the streetside stir,
I curse my newfound home.
No human skill will raise
my love to bloom into a man.
Shot by cowards in his bed
at the tender age of nine.
Cry mother my child Patrick’s
dead in Belfast 69-- [clapping]
-I understand today that they’re
bringing down their barricades in order
that the authority might
clean their streets for them.
Having littered and turned
the southside into a filthy place,
now they expect the municipal
authority or the commission
authority to do
their cleaning up for them.
Now, I want to say something
this afternoon and underline it,
that as far as I am concerned,
the protestant people have had enough
of this condoning of pulvering
and we say no to Rome.
[crowd cheering]
-On August 15th, 1969, British troops
began arriving in Northern Ireland,
with the announced aim of keeping
the peace between the two communities.
In reality, they were there to prop up
the state faced with
a virtual insurrection.
Civil Rights movement had
suddenly become irrelevant.
After August, it was
too late for reforms.
-Following the failure
of the 52-62 campaign, which
failed fundamentally because
it didn’t have the mass
support within the Nationalist
ghetto areas of the occupied North.
There was a reanalysis
and because of a certain amount
of demoralization which
resulted from that failure,
there was a reformist element which
gained control of the movement.
As a result, in 1969 when
the Nationalist ghetto areas
of the occupied North were
attacked by Loyalist extremists,
the Republican Army was not in a position
to defend the Nationalist people.
Initially, there was a sectarian
response to those attacks,
and the armed ability
of the Nationalist people was built up.
However, those people who had
initially formed the political core
of the Republican Army reanalyzing
that situation, that is the 1969 crisis,
realized that the sectarian element was
merely a symptom of British
imperialist rule.
Consequently, it was a necessity
to reanalyze a response to that symptom.
This led to the emergence of what
became known as a Provisional
IRA and the Provisional
IRA was to be distinguished
because it advocated
the necessity of an armed struggle
to be directed at the main
core of the problem,
which was British imperialism
and not a reformist approach
to sectarianism, which was merely
a symptom of British imperialist rule.
For us, this war is not just a war
of shooting British soldiers,
it is also about coming
to a final political objective,
which is the creation of a 32 county
Democratic Socialist Republic,
to be controlled by the ordinary
people for their own benefit.
-Stand still, you’re under
arrest for breaking the-- [?]
[background noise]
-As I speak to you, the security
forces are very fully engaged
in the task of dealing effectively
with the law-breakers in our community.
The army is holding an area
of the Lower Falls under
strict control of movement
for the rest of this weekend,
subject only to such relaxations as are
necessary to prevent actual hardship
and to allow people tomorrow
to fulfill their religious obligations.
Details of these
controls, and of the areas
to which they apply have
already been announced.
We all regret, of course,
the inconvenience caused to decent
law-abiding people in this area
who constitute the great majority.
We are determined to rid
them and Northern Ireland
as a whole, of the terrorists
in their midst.
-In the middle of 1970, following
a sectarian attack on one
of the Nationalist ghetto areas
in Belfast, the short strand area.
The Provisionals were in a position
to successfully defend
that particular ghetto,
where the Nationalist people were
outnumbered something like 10 to 1.
The following week, which was July 1970,
in a direct response to the ability
of the Republican Army to defend
the Nationalist ghetto areas,
the British Army occupied one major
Nationalist ghetto areas, the Lower Falls.
From the Provisional’s point
of view, this was full of indication
of why armed struggle was
necessary because this was
the first physical manifestation
of British imperialism since the 1920s.
For the first time, the people
could relate to the Provisionals’
claim that sectarianism was
in fact, just a symptom,
and that the main enemy was
British imperialism itself.
Here was something with
which they could identify.
-I just turned down the corner of [?]
street about 20 past 12, Friday night.
Sunday morning, couldn’t
get home to my own home.
It was only around the corner
and what actually, seen a man
getting shot down, shot through
the head by the Scotch troops,
the corner of Coventry Road.
The young ones was about 30 minutes coming
and they had trouble getting their mom.
I think their mom has since died.
-Going to chapel
this morning, we were searched
for [?] and the on thing
[?] chapel this morning.
-It was like hell opening
for sinners at the [?]
it was worse than the battle at Mullins.
They were going at their houses
and racking their houses and all.
If you’d seen that montage you could
cry your eyes out looking at it.
-[?] at a quarter to six
my wife took birth.
She probably hit with teargas.
She was taken to Robert Tully
Hospital [?] Expecting a baby.
Baby was born a quarter
to three the next morning.
Baby still [?] was taken
at gunpoint from my house.
Yes, I was taken at gunpoint
over the Robert Tully Hospital.
Taken in to Robert Tully
Hospital to see my wife
and I was down there with
their guns on me at the corner.
At the very bedroom my wife was
laying and they had their guns on me.
They marched me like a trooper
down the street again.
Got me at the bottom
of the street and stood
me up against the wall and searched me.
They made me lay on my face,
and they took me around the house.
Now, I’m at my house
again. They racked my home.
I had just come around to the house
again, they just away, they racked home.
Dogs are had for our people,
they set them free.
Babies clothes, the meter,
beds, they tore them apart.
The food is scattered all
over the place searching for.
They went upstairs, bunk
beds took them down.
They took my wife’s bed down,
wardrobes took all that down.
They broke the windows in the back.
They’re animals, nothing
but short, just animals.
A scotch man, they were walking
down the street, they were
walking by, got the wee
van outside the door [?].
They broke every window in the van
they said, "This’ll stop bullets."
[?] we fix their 4,500 of them,
armed with tanks, machine
guns, the lot [?] They fixed
IRA 20 or 30 of men were guns.
They were tired of murder, which I have
murdered and which I’ll
continue to murder.
That’s the British army,
professional looters
professional robbers,
professional thieves.
[crowd yelling]
-It was with the occupation
of the Falls Road that the Nationalist
population began to see the British
Army clearly as the enemy,
not as a neutral police force.
It was also the beginning
of what has since become
the longest war in the history
of English-Irish conflict.
[shouting]
[gun shots]
-Shortly after the Falls Road
occupation, the guerrilla
war started, but it was
a new kind of war.
The IRA did not just ambush
British soldiers, they also
launched a bombing campaign
against British economic interests.
These actions have on occasion led
to terrible tragedy as with the Lamont
restaurant bombing of February 1978,
in which 14 people were killed.
Nonetheless, civilian casualties,
as a result of the Provisionals
guerrilla war have been relatively
low for the bombings are in fact,
systematically proceeded by a warning.
By August 1971, the number of monthly
bombings had risen to over 90.
The British government,
which directly reimburses
businesses for all war
damage that they suffer
was beginning to pay a very high
price for its Northern Irish coloring.
This single bombing of a Belfast
hotel caused no deaths
or injuries but it did cause
more than £2 million damage.
Against this guerilla campaign,
the British government hit back with
a measure that had always worked well
in the past, The Special Powers Act.
-They burst on the door
by counting on us to five.
They didn’t wait till we would
get up and answer the door.
They were in the bedroom
before we were dressed.
They told my husband, "You’re getting
arrested down to the Special Powers Act."
-It is with understandable reluctance
that one uses these exceptional powers.
This is not action taken against
any responsible and law-abiding section
of the community, nor is it in any way
punitive or indiscriminate,
its benefits should be felt,
not least in those places
where violent men have
exercised a certain sway
by threat and intimidation over
decent and responsible men and women.
The main target of the present
operation is the Irish Republican
Army, which has been responsible
for recent acts of terrorism.
[gun shots]
-On August 9th, 1971, 350 Nationalists
were arrested in dawn raids.
In the rioting that day,
14 people were killed.
[yelling]
[gun shots]
[music]
-The introduction of Internment
has given the [?] myself a chance to get
a grip of the gunman because our main
problem isn’t the local population,
it’s just the IRA gunmen
that we are interested in.
[music]
Through the little streets
of Belfast In the dark of early morn
British soldiers came marauding
Wrecking little homes with scorn.
Heedless of the crying children
Dragging fathers from their beds Beating
sons while helpless mothers Watched
the blood flow from their heads
Armoured cars and tanks and guns
Came to take away our sons
But every man will stand
behind The Men Behind the Wire
Not for them a judge or jury Or indeed
a crime at all Being Irish means they’re
guilty So we’re guilty one and all
Round the world the truth will echo
CromweIl’s men are here again
England’s name again is sullied
In the eyes of honest men
-There was no man to [?]
These people have been
sitting from half-past 4:00
on Monday morning till noon,
and they’re still in the same conditions.
They’ve been put on their huts, as I say,
like a pigs, and the only
time they got out,
as for interrogation by the bastards
of the RUC special Branch.
As everybody well knows, when
they’re going for interrogation
with the special branch-- -Just
as Internment was introduced,
the Nationalists began to realize
that the internees had not only been
beaten up, which everyone expected
but that some had been severely tortured.
Electric shocks, druggings,
deprivation of sleep, food,
water, all came under the official
term of interrogation.
In 1976, the European
commission of human rights found
the British government guilty
of torturing certain internee,
Britain promised such interrogation
methods would never again be used.
But in 1978, two different studies,
one by Amnesty International
and another by an independent
tribunal of jurist concluded
that brutality and torture
against Nationalist
suspects remained a widespread practice.
-torture periods because I was
in Springfield road torture
center and I’d been held
for about three days at the time,
I had undergone the usual
torture treatment.
That is beating,
threats, the hot and cold
treatment, hot water,
and so on and so forth.
I was brought into a room where
special branch was there as they’d
torture us and they’d pull
the truncheon from the drawer,
and told me that the methods
of interrogation
could be two ways, the easy
way or the hard way.
I was very frightened.
I told him I wanted the easy way,
and he gave me a slip of paper and a pen
and told me that I was to give him
the names of two prominent IRA men,
two IRA volunteers officers.
I said I didn’t know any.
He left the room to get the heavy
squad, these are the gorillas,
absolutely, the big people,
and that if I hadn’t had
the names by the time
he returned, I could
expect the full treatment.
He went away. I was pissed of at this.
He came back, "Do you know any names?"
I said, "Well, I don’t
know anybody, but."
When I said but, he jumped and he said,
"Right, Mr. Austin, we know you’re
a very certain guy, you tell us
names and we let you go,
you go home to your family."
I said the names
and they were, Doherty O’conor
and Joe Cahill, whose names
were on TV every night.
[?] dragged me from the room
back into the cell, but these
are one of the many, many,
many stories that happened.
This is the humorous
side of interrogation.
Now, the other side is the two
streets from here, last
week, a boy of 19 was arrested
and was beaten to death
by the special branch
and by the British soldiers.
This is a general practice, and they’re
beaten to death or near to death.
This is what is all about.
-I am an officer with the Northern
Ireland Prison Service .
Let me tell you about my job.
It’s about the variety, like
driving, using modern equipment,
escorting prisoners to court,
but mostly dealing with people.
I work with great mates
and I’m earning over
£80 a week, and that’s without overtime.
The prison service needs people.
People like you. Get the facts. Send
the coupon from a newspaper now.
-Since 1971, virtually every
adult in the Nationalist
ghettos had been arrested
and interrogated at least once.
In 1978, there were over 3,000 men
and women in prisons and prison
camps in Ireland and Britain,
the largest one being Long Kesh,
just outside of Belfast.
Through the years, Nationalist
prisoners have struggled
repeatedly using hunger
strikes, prison insurrections,
and escapes in order to assert
their rights as prisoners of war,
rights which were recognized
by the British government
before March 1976
but which have since been denied to all
Nationalists arrested after that date.
[music].
-When Internment was introduced
in 1971, there was a spontaneous
reaction by the Nationalist
people to this particular
repressive measure which allowed
the Republican Army
to re-accelerate its war.
The main emphasis within that war
was an economic bombing strategy.
The whole emphasis of the armed
struggle was a destabilization program
to prevent politics as it had manifested
itself within the occupied North,
from stabilizing itself and consolidating
some sort of base for itself.
Then, because most of the political
parties were already backed
by commercial interests, the best
way of obtaining that destabilization
was with an economic bombing strategy.
[bombs going off]
-It’s very difficult to suggest
any particular security
action that can avoid this kind of thing.
This particular devastation
apparently was caused
by a lorry hijacked
in Joy Street yesterday.
Now, there must be some
people who saw the hijackers.
There must be some people who know
who’s involved in this bombing.
I doubt very much whether there are
very many people organizing this.
I doubt whether there are very
many people taking part in this,
but it is high time that every
citizen of Northern Ireland,
quite irrespective
of religion, quite irrespective
of politics, came forward
and said, "I have information."
That, in my view, is
the only adequate means
of dealing with this sort of situation.
[bombs going off]
-How about SDLP, how
do you feel about them?
[crosstalking]
-Is there anybody in this part of Belfast
that you place your confidence in?
-Yes, the police.
[laughter]
-As the war accelerated after Internment,
the Nationalist not only
rejected government authority,
but also the moderate Nationalist parties
who still hoped to reform the state.
Bypassing the politicians,
they began to deal
directly with the problems
faced by the community.
This meant building parks and daycare
centers for children as well as meeting
places for the elderly in areas which had
never had the slightest social services.
Neighborhood People’s
Assemblies were formed to solve
housing, unemployment,
and other day-to-day problems.
All this activity culminated
with the formation of entire
self-governing areas that became
known as Free Derry and Free Belfast.
The large Nationalist
community in Derry refused
to pay rents and taxes
to the Unionists government.
The police and the army
were kept out of the area
by barricades openly manned by the IRA.
In effect, Derry had seceded
from Northern Ireland.
[music]
-On October 11th, 1969, there were
riots in the Loyalist districts
of Belfast, so the city government
took the public buses off the road.
Three days later, they were rolling
again in Loyalist areas, but it was
three months before bus service was
restored to the Nationalist ghettos.
Forced back upon their own resources,
some enterprising local people
went over to England and began
bringing back secondhand taxis.
This was the beginning of the Falls
Taxi Association, the people’s taxis.
[background conversations]
---for the taxis, I don’t think
any of us would have gone to work
because there’s no buses on the road,
took large buses off the road,
the Whiterock Road buses off the road.
It’s about two miles to walk
down to the Whiterock
Road so you would be late
for work-- [crosstalk]
-[?]
-The taxi rate are very obliged.
-We could point out that the Falls
Taxi Association is now among
the biggest self-help organization
in the north of Ireland.
We now have 350 drivers,
450 persons, self-employed actually
working on the routes
that we have specified before.
The media treat us very unkindly
with the fact that in Newry
for instance, the second-highest
unemployed town in the north of Ireland,
where the minister of commerce got
seven minutes on the national news
and the national press to the effect
that he had created 15 jobs.
He stated at that it costs
£17,000 to create
a job for one person in Northern Ireland,
yet we have never received any credibility
or acknowledgment from any source
to the fact that we have created
350 permanent jobs for people that,
because of the areas where
they live, the Nationalist
ghettos, they can’t find
employment anywhere else.
They have to remain in the areas.
-This is the lower part of the Falls now
are coming down under
the area of Whiterock.
This is the general route when you’re
coming down under the center of the town.
As I say, we come down
to this bottom of this road,
there’s quite heavy bit of traffic on it,
but at one time we used to have
to go through these areas when
there was riots, bombings
and hijacking of buses and whatnot.
The whole thing about it was,
not during one of those times did
any of our taxis ever stop or fail
to run a service in these areas.
This is why the public has shown
concern to use the taxis
because their point of view was
that we have gotten them to work.
We’re dependable.
We’re a far more efficient service
and quicker, and we are cheap.
This is why they depend
on us at the moment.
They’re now pushing the [?]
of the Whiterock which at one time
was a tremendous for riding
and hijacked buses at that time
during confrontations
with the security forces.
One example, during internment
day, there was quite a few people
shot up around this area, and still
even then, the taxis still ran.
This is the lower floors
end of it where most
of the raiding and burning had
taken place, and as I said,
during those times when the taxis
was traveling through it, the raiders
were courteous enough to stop
throwing for that few seconds,
and to let us through, so as to get
to the safety of their own
people back home.
Coming up to the place,
and I recall there was
a blast, and this is where
a lot of the RUC had turned
their guns on innocent people
at that time so they did.
As I said, the taxis didn’t bar, they just
kept on running in and out the stage.
They took various in-routes,
as long as they got the people home.
They went over barricades and everything
so they did, and this was the whole point.
The taxis never did stop running.
I think this was a thorn
on the side of the security forces.
-Harassment of the taxis,
it’s a general thing.
If you look behind us now,
this is a normal procedure where
they threw up roadblocks, stopped
motorists, especially taxis,
and took the driving license
of the driver, and make them
sit for anything up to 30
minutes, search the vehicle,
make the passengers stand
on the side of the road.
Sometimes they attempt to arrest
the drivers for unknown reasons, most
of the drivers are well-known on the road,
they’re on it seven days a week.
We have to react when they do
arrest a driver, and our alternative
and the only weapon that we have
is to set up our own roadblocks.
What we would do, seal
off the vehicle that would be trying
to arrest the driver, put taxis
at the front, to the side,
and the back it and hand him on.
Generally, that works,
and they release the driver.
If they do arrest the driver and take
him away, what we normally do then
would be block off the main arteries
into the city, when we do this,
we can close the entire city
within a matter of minutes.
We only need to close off three
roads, and that brings
a complete standstill
to the entire city center.
Generally, this serves the purpose,
and the driver is released
after a short period.
-In 1971, nationalist civilians
became increasingly the random targets
of a campaign of no-warning bombs,
kidnappings, and assassinations.
In other words, death squads.
It was a loyalist reaction.
The British army paid scant attention
to the loyalist kind of militaries.
Their major concern was in dealing
with the new wave of mass
demonstrations by nationalists,
protesting against internment.
The streets of Northern Ireland
soon became a real-life laboratory
for the army’s experiments
in controlling an insurgent population,
and the nationalists were
the human guinea pigs.
One of the techniques was the use
of so-called harmless weapons, including
the not-so harmless CS gas, which
was first widely used in Vietnam.
CS gas is in fact, lethal, and can cause
permanent damage to the lungs,
stomach, and eyes.
The gas, the water cannons,
the burning of matches,
the mass arrests, all had
little apparent effect.
Week after week, large demonstrations
were held against internment.
Finally, in Derry, on January
30th, 1972, the British
army decided to use a more
effective technique, live arms.
[sound  of distress]
[background noise]
[somber music]
-[?] one soldier come, got
out before they even stopped
the sirens and tanks got
on his knee and shot everywhere,
and about seconds after soldiers
followed him doing the same thing.
We heard them from
that flat there calling,
"Don’t stop shooting,
shoot the Irish bastards."
Lieutenant-Colonel Derek Wilford:
I say again, that I hesitate
to call anyone
liers, but the facts are,
we were fired at first,
and we retaliated in the only
way which was possible to us.
-No weapon, they had no stone,
they had nothing, they was
just standing, and as we turned,
they started firing.
Well, we heard the shots.
We heard a few shots,
and as we turned, he fell dead.
-He went to tell the soldiers
to stop firing, you can see
the blood running there, where
the gentleman was shot at.
That’s all I can tell, I was too shocked.
-I never saw it, even on the worst
film I ever looked at, that was
massacre, it was mass murder,
and I don’t care who hears me say it.
I never hope to live
to see the day that will
ever happen again, where
it’s pure murder. Murder.
-The day they come in shooting,
there was no doubt about it.
From their commander box, they were
shooting even before the commander
box said, and there wasn’t
a nail bomb thrown in this area.
No, there wasn’t a rifle shot fired.
They were the people who
had done the shooting,
and then the police bagged
them up from the wild fear.
The police, they shot dead more of us.
That’s what caused
that lad’s death there.
He tried to help two
other lads, and they were
shot down, just like a bloody dog.
Just like animals, we were shot at.
I have no doubt this has been planned.
They called off the arranged
meeting, and the place they had
the meeting, and the girl talks
to us so they could shoot us.
They didn’t care who we were, didn’t
care, man, woman, or child here.
A youngster died this morning
where they were run
over by [?] then went back
over the top of her again.
What are we going to do? Are we going
to stand by idly and watch it all?
[somber music]
-Following Bloody Sunday,
there was a tremendous
upsurge of nationalists
feeling throughout Ireland.
Large demonstrations were held
north, and south, and in Dublin,
a 30,000 strong crowd burnt
down the British Embassy.
For the first time, the nationalists’
resistance had assumed threatening
proportions in the South
where Britain still had
important economic interests.
The British government had little
choice but to make major concessions.
On March 24th, 1972, the union’s
government was suspended
by London, and Britain promised
to release the internment.
That Easter, as the nationalists
in Derry, held their annual commemoration
of the 1916 rising, the resistance
movement was apparently in its
strongest position since
the start of the war.
-[?] of their destiny.
On one hand, if we’re determined,
if we are courageous, if we are
resonant, and if we are
strong-willed enough to recognize
that compromise will not
solve our country’s problems.
If we recognize that compromise
never achieved anything,
and that compromise never
will achieve anything,
and that therefore our fight must
continue, and that we will win that fight,
then we are truly following
in the footsteps
of the men, and the women,
and the and the boys
and girls of Easter Week.
[applause]
-Suspending operations at Christmas
and at Easter and in implementing
a three-day unilateral truce
on March 10th, 11th, and 12th last.
In addition, we have held
wide-ranging talks with various groups
and parties with a view to holding
an all-Irish conference.
Would you pass them down, please?
-Yes. Isn’t it politically really
difficult, if not impossible,
for Mr. Whitelaw to do as you suggest
in view of the high emotion that’s been
engendered amongst Protestants,
particularly with the forthcoming weekend?
-My reply to that would be this.
If Mr. Whitelaw and his government
are sincerely interested
in peace, then he’d be prepared
to discuss our terms with us.
-We were anxious to discuss
our proposals with the representatives
of the British government but we were
determined that if there was going
to be a truce, it was going
to be a bilateral truce.
It was going to be that would be
publicly recognized by the British
and that would be conditions
that would be binding on the British
army as well as on the Republican
army, and this was done.
Then we went to London
and we met Mr. Whitelaw
and members of his political
staff, and we listened
to what he had to say, which
didn’t amount to very much.
Then we presented our own
document, our own proposals,
and which we called upon
the British government
to recognize the right
of the Irish people as a whole,
acting as a single unit,
to decide the future of Ireland.
We called upon the British government
to withdraw all their forces
by a specified date.
Mr. Whitelaw didn’t
turn down our proposals.
He said he would refer them
back to his cabinet, and this is
what I believe brought about
the ending of the truce.
That Mr. Whitelaw went back to Ted
Heath who was Prime Minister
at the time, showed him
our document, our proposals.
Ted Heath read them and turned
around and said, "Well,
I don’t think there’s
anything can be done here.
You’d better break the truce
as soon as you can."
In fact, the truce broke
on the following Sunday night.
It nearly broke that morning
in Portadown over the severe
provocation, and it broke
on that Sunday night.
It was inevitable and in view
of the behavior of the British
troops in Lenadoon in Belfast
that the truce was going to break.
It broke with tragic results
for everybody concerned.
Tragic results for the Irish
people, for the English people.
Tragic results for the British
troops and the IRA volunteers
and the civilians who have
been killed since then.
I hope that the day will come, again,
when British representatives realize that
the only way to a permanent
peace in Ireland is
to meed to representatives
of the Republican movement
and negotiate with them
a phased and orderly withdrawal.
[background noise]
-Two days after the peace
talks in London, the truce
broke down in a Lenadoon
housing estate of Belfast.
There, 16 displaced nationalist
families had been allocated homes
by the Public Housing Authority,
but the homes bordered
a loyalist district,
and the Ulster Defence
Association, the largest
of several loyalist paramilitary
groups, opposed the move.
In turn, the British army refused
to permit the families
to enter the houses.
In the confrontation that day
in Lenadoon, six civilians were shot dead.
In the next week, 13 British
soldiers were killed.
It was the end of a truce which
had lasted barely two weeks.
[explosions]
[music]
[explosion]
[screaming]
Following the breakdown
of the truce, the Provisionals
launched their biggest
military offensive to date.
The commercial centers of Derry,
Belfast and other major
towns began to look as if they had
been blitzed from the air.
In the space of a few days,
British investment was hit
with millions of pounds of losses,
and because of warnings,
there were virtually no
civilian casualties, until July
21st when bombs placed
in Belfast killed nine civilians.
The British government and media
seized the opportunity given by Bloody
Friday as it was to be called,
to present the IRA as mad terrorists.
It was only several months later
that an investigation by the London
Sunday Times revealed that hour-long
warnings for all the bombs
had been given
to the Samaritan organization,
which had, in turn, notified the police.
For some reason, however,
several of the bomb alerts
were not passed on by the police
to the target areas.
The result was several innocent
people were killed and injured
and a tremendous propaganda
victory for the British government.
[explosions]
-A lot of people assume
that this distortion was
bad journalism when, in fact,
that was not accurate,
for this distortion was
a deliberate tactic within
the context of Frank Kitson’s
theory of counterinsurgency
because Kitson has recognized
the important role
that the media has to play
in a counterinsurgency campaign
and has always strived to use
the media as a platform
where necessary to distort
the image of the Republican Army
as a liberation movement
and to project this image
of the British occupation forces
as some kind of police service.
-10 days after Bloody Friday,
22,000 British troops occupied
the nationalist ghettos in a move
code-named Operation Motorman.
It was the end of free
Derry and free Belfast.
-Let Ireland see, there’s
the power. There’s the power there.
-That’s the power of the [crosstalk]
-You can’t disobey
against a man like that.
-The cream of the British
Army and paratroopers.
A couple of thousand go over them house
last night and cut off their limbs.
They didn’t give us a chance.
-They’ve taken over [crosstalk]
-Arrange a meeting with Jack [?] and-
-It’s a blarney.
-It’s a lot of bloody hooey.
-Yankee blarney.
-We are damned up here. We are
getting murdered up here. Murdered.
-I have made it perfectly clear that these
operations are designed to protect
the whole community, to remove
the fear of intimidation by terrorists
from the community, from
whatever it may come.
I think that after the work
of Her Majesty’s government over
these recent months, the patience
of Her Majesty’s government,
the work to convince
the minority community
that we are determined
to give them a fair deal.
I trust this friction will not
arise. I see no reason why it should.
The security forces are there
to protect the whole community.
-There are over 1,000 different British
firms throughout Ireland,
North, and South,
controlling more than 60% of the country’s
total industrial activity.
One week after Operation
Motorman, moderate nationalist
politicians were having
talks with William Whitelaw.
In order to pacify the nationalists,
the British government
was willing to force
concessions from the unionists.
Finally, in January 1974,
a power-sharing government was formed
in which moderate nationalists were
given certain cabinet positions.
It was at Northern Ireland
first, also a last.
The problem was that after 300 years
of ascendancy, the loyalist people
would only support a government
that could guarantee their privileges.
Power-sharing with
the nationalists was unthinkable.
On May 14, 1974, loyalist extremist
groups controlling workers in the key
electric generating plants launched
a strike against the new government.
When the British Army
refused to intervene,
the success of the strike was assured.
Within two weeks,
the power-sharing government fell.
Britain had been caught
in a contradiction of trying
to reform a state that was
simply irreformable.
It could only be
consolidated by the physical
crushing of the nationalist resistance.
The other solution, the only
possible one for the nationalists
remained the destruction
of the Northern Ireland state itself.
The struggle in the north had
passed the point of no return.
-We have decided to protest
against internment.
Despite the ban on parade,
we have decided that we will
parade tomorrow through
the streets of Derry.
[crowd singing]
[background noise]
[music]
-This is Turf Lodge, a housing
estate in West Belfast.
It’s a nationalist
district like most others
which means an unemployment
rate of over 20%.
[parade music]
-It also means a military
occupation, endless raids
and arrests, and the constant
threat of violent death.
[parade music continues]
-On October 4th, 1976,
12-year-old Brian Stewart
of Turf Lodge was playing
in front of his home
when he was killed by a plastic
bullet fired by a British foot patrol.
At the time, there was
no rioting or gun battles
in the area which made the killing
all the more senseless.
Since then, the women of Turf Lodge
have gone out into the streets each
and every day to protest against
the continued British army presence.
[whistles]
[background noise]
-Turf Lodge really started it and all
the women come out with
their [?] whistles.
Now, three or four months later, all
the nicest areas in [?]
Murphy are going [?]
they’re nearly all out with
their [?] whistles again.
The women are starting to show the lead.
They recognize the need for them
to work on the par with the man.
From the start, women have been
involved in the military campaign
but now, the woman who usually
stayed at home are all coming
out and begin to feel
the power that they have
when they’re all bonded
together and coming out
as a force and making
their presence felt in the area.
The Brits obviously
don’t like this at all.
If there’s only one
or two women, they think
they can abuse them
but before they know it,
there’s hundreds out and the Brits are
chased out of this particular area.
Last week at the elections,
you remember they had
the elections and we had
a picket outside.
We were telling the people,
"Why are you going to vote?
You’re going to vote
for British imperialism?
You’ve had it for 100 years,
and what has it achieved?
[background noise]
[gunshots]
[shouting]
-In August 1976, in the midst
of the continuing war,
a peace movement was
formed which tried to regroup moderate
nationalist and loyalist women.
For the first time in a long
time, Northern Ireland
became front-page news
throughout the world.
The peace movement was
significant as a truly remarkable
media event which, however,
never quite took root in reality.
-[?] the formation after
three children had been
killed in an accident
on the Upper Falls Road.
What has happened was
that an IRA act of service
unit organized to ambush
the British Army.
On the way to the ambush, they were
chased by a British patrol.
The patrol opened fire
on the car. The driver was killed.
The car obviously went out of control
and hit the three children.
At the beginning of that, there was
obvious sympathies towards the family.
People were very sympathetic.
People were very sorry what had happened.
The peace movement led by [?]
a local pro-British journalist, used
this opportunity to launch a movement
that was directed against the IRA.
From it’s [?] formation, it condemned IRA
violence but didn’t condemn
British army violence.
It condemned the shooting
of businessmen but allowed
the shooting of innocent
Catholic civilians.
It progressed solely because
it was well-financed.
We believe that it’s financed
solely by the British
government and by pro-British
elements and by big business.
It continued to about January
of this year, fairly strong.
What happened then was in the West
Belfast area, the British
army deliberately sent
in the paratroop regiment who
as you can remember were
responsible for the massacres
in Derry, the shooting of Majella O’Hare,
the schoolgirl who was
murdered by the British army,
and other mysterious
shootings in the country areas
the British army were directly
responsible for those.
The paratroop regiment came in typical
SAS fighting, house raiding,
abuse, beating people up, in-depth
interrogation, and in actual fact,
they threw a young boy out
of a window at the interrogation
center that I mentioned earlier
on, Springfield Barracks.
This, a fact of life, alienated
the people even more from
the British army, and the Republican
Movement were seen
to be the only ones who cared
and who could provide the alternative
to this type of attitude
that the British army had adopted.
Also this campaign of harassment
by the British paratroop regiment.
The Peace Movement issued no
statements, didn’t condemn the violence,
and in fact, issued statements saying
that they support law and order
and that we nationalist
people should do the same.
The problem was how can you support law
and order when law and order is kicking
your door in and beating you up?
[background noise]
[screaming and shouting]
Here, take him away.
[?]
We'll arrest you as well.
We're going that side.
[?]
Can you come up [?]?
-[?] You're on TV.
-He's well [?] his family [?]
-Tell me about [?] [crosstalk]
-He'll hardly [?]
[background noise]
[music]
[applause]
[?] appreciate it, [?].
They [?], didn't they?
Wiped your [?] away.
[music]
[background noise]
[gunshots]
-[?]
As you know this camp officially
starts, when you're on this camp,
do not leave the room, and you’re
not to move without permission.
When you are on the camp, you’ll
use numbers instead of your name.
There’ll be numbers from one
to three, besides, there’s
a guard who’ll have to stay
in the camp 24 hours a day.
I’m the TO. I’ll be teaching
in the weapons, and you’re not to handle
a weapon until I tell you,
or you ask permission.
Well, [?].
All right this is the AR-15.
The first thing you do, when
you take possession of any weapons,
you check it for safe, if there’s
a magazine on it, you release it.
To check the page by touch,
and by site on possible,
check the safe, for the [?] cork.
Always point the weapon
in a safe direction.
Never take anyone’s word
that the weapon is safe.
Right now, I’ll name the parts
there on the top, there
on the right, there on the left,
and there on the bottom.
-The Republicans quite clearly
have outlined their proposals,
for the future riot that’s
called earner of the new Ireland.
In New Ireland, we invented
self-governed communities, that is
the people on the grind, will
have a say in their lives,
will have a say in how
their area is run, and will have
the dignity that the workers have
lacked for so long in Ireland.
Those community clusters will be
affiliated to a regional council who
in turn will be under direction of what’s
known as the provincial council.
Ireland is divided
in four equal provinces,
they have Ulster, Munster,
Leinster, and Connaught.
These councils at every step will
take into consideration the voices
of the people from the ground,
to the provincial governments,
who intern will be affiliated
to the federal parliament of Ireland.
This is a solution
to the problem of Ireland.
The solution is not to get rid
of the Brits, and exchange one master
for another master, the Irish capitalist,
the solution is to give the control,
and the wealth of Ireland
to the people of Ireland,
and allow them to administrate
what they need for themselves.
The point that I made earlier on about
the peace people, or so-called people.
They are actively working against us.
They have said that what
we need is more bureaucracy,
and we need to have more
civil servants ruin our lives.
We quite simply said
the solution to Ireland is
the people, the Irish people
who can provide a solution,
and that solution will be found only
under a socialist system, and that’s it.
[music]
[people chattering]
[background noise]
[music]
-[singing]
This Ireland of ours
has for long been half free
Six counties are under
John Bull’s tyranny
And still, the Valley is greatly to blame
For shirking his part in the patriot game
I don’t mind a bit if I shoot down police
Their luck is for long
Never guardians of peace
But yet as deserters I’m never letting
those rebels who sold
out the patriot game
Now I am dying, my body all holes
I think of those traitors
who bargained and sold
I’m sorry my rifle has not done the same
For the Quislings who
sold out the patriot game
Transcription by Johannes Grenzfurthner [monochrom.at]...
...as part of an artistic research program on
UK colonial history; please help improve this version 1.0